墨西哥某处
只有白痴美国佬才会
Only a hardheaded gringo... Would come down here...
单枪匹马参加营救
On a rescue mission... ALL ALONE
这美国佬什么也不会说的
This gringo is not going to talk.
那就宰了他
Then kill him.
快，将军还在等我们
C'mon, the General's expecting us.
别用你的枪
You can't use your gun...
用他自己的
...Shoot him with his.
不管用
lt's not working.
这混蛋的枪没有撞针
This asshole's gun has no firing pin.
别管他了
Leave him.
我的狗狗们可很久没吃过活物了
The dogs haven't had to kill for their food in a while.
下一次，朋友
Next time, amigo,
想好再来
plan ahead.
我是不是太残忍了
Oh, I'm such a bad Catholic.
哪能，你就是脑子里有虫
No, you're just sick in the head.
别忘了将军的钱
Don't forget the General's money.
这美国佬贿赂错了警察
That gringo bribed the wrong cop...
还带了把没撞针的枪
...and brought a gun with no firing pin.
狗狗们干活了！
汉尼拔
史密斯上校
墨西哥另一处
Catch me if you can I'm in 'em oId schooI BarkIey's
Back to the fence puffin' on that Bob Marley
FIow Iike oregano
You aIready know my competition's stiffer than RonaId Regan
Let it go
For you be a mother...
You scrap it's too animated like The lncredibles
Let this beef go around like the tenty six's
lt's young Game of flame
Welcome to the House of Pain
大头
博斯克·巴库斯
我的宝贝儿在哪儿，软蛋？
Where's my girl, fool?
她很好，伙计，就在那，好的不得了
She cool, man. She in there. She's still fine as hell.
就这样？你玩完了？
So that's it? Bada- bing, you out of the game?
已经被人踢出来了？
Done with the whole trade?
- 没错 - 问题就在这，博斯克
- Yeah. - Well, that's the problem, Bosco.
你要么继续干
You either keep doing that,
要么就在墨西哥监狱里呆上15年
or you do a 1 5- year bid in a Mexican prison
跟奇托的堂兄搭个伴
with Cheeto's cousin in there.
老规矩，路你自己选吧，老兄
Same old shit. You choose how to flush the toilet, brother.
是走阳关道，还是独木桥
That's right. Easy way or the hard way.
来啊！
Come on!
好了，兵蛋子
Okay, street soldier. Shit.
你可要想清楚，大头，咱们可是老朋友了
But watch yourself, B.A., now, you gonna lose your oldest friend here.
你好吗，宝贝？想我了吗？
What's up, girl? You miss me?
我可想你了，没错，想的不得了，宝贝
Because I missed you. Yes, I did. lt's been too long, baby.
想死你了
Way too long.
真见鬼了
Heck of a place.
这地方美的一塌糊涂
Just a heck of a beautiful place.
这儿是度假别墅吗？我太喜欢这儿了
ls this a time- share? l'd love to get in on this.
我超爱这个圣达菲调调，你也来吧，图克
l like this whole Santa Fe motif you got going here, Tuco.
非常亚利桑那，非常有混合气息 很好，很好
lt's very Arizona, very Tex- Mex. lt's good. lt's good.
真想把我小弟叫来
Maybe we can get the guy at my six
一起吃烧烤，意下如何？
to whip up a couple of quesadiches, you know?
小帅
贝克中尉
给我使劲烧，让火星人都看见
l want the flames to be seen by the Martians.
烧死这个丑美国佬
Americano, gringo.
- 陆军特工 - 你在说谁？
- Army lntelligence. - Who's that?
- 你，老兄 - 才不
- You, man. - No.
你也没什么脑子嘛，否则也不会困在轮胎里
You're not so intelligent because you're stuck in some tires.
这很爽，这很爽
I'm happy. I'm happy.
再没比这更爽的了，不是吗？
Doesn't get any better than this, right?
- 就跟做梦一样 - 是啊！
- I'm living the dream. - You are!
你来这里本应该
You're gonna come here...
先把我装进袋子扔到边境
...to throw me in a bag across the border...
可你居然先去勾引我老婆
...but instead you have sex with my wife.
嗯，首先，她的确很火爆
Well, first of all, she's so hot,
而且我们都恨你，所以这是顺理成章的
and we both hate you. So that's just sort of how it...
- 早上好！ - 早上好，老兄！
- Good morning! Good morning, man!
好戏开始了
Now it's a party!
- 你就这点儿能耐？ - 那就来点厉害的！
- ls that your best shot? - Now it's a party, man!
A- ha, okay, what's up? Shut up
Whoa!
Okay, what's up? Shut up
l got a pocket full of B's Cocoa weed and ain't got no place to go...
哦，见鬼！
Oh, hell, no.
慢慢坐到一边
Slide over slowly.
你这是抢劫吗？
You jacking me?
太阳打西边出来了？
What is this, opposite day?
我不是贼，可要是我不及时去救一个朋友，他就死定了
I'm not a thief. But if I don't reach my friend in time, then he dies.
你如果不是个贼，那我肯定你也不是个杀人犯
lf you ain't a thief, I guarantee you ain't a killer.
左手放开方向盘，右手放开变速器，快
Take your left hand off the wheel and your right hand off the shifter now.
你不会冲我的脑袋开枪的，欧巴桑
You ain't gonna shoot me in the head, pops.
你知道自己下不了手
You know that ain't happening.
你脑袋进水了怎么着？
What the hell's wrong with you, man?
居然对一个陌生人开枪
You shoot a total stranger?
我根本就不认识你，该死
l don't even know you, fool. Damn.
皮外伤而已
lt'll heal, I promise.
- 拿着，用它包扎 - 我知道怎么止血，白痴
- Here, wrap it in this. - I know how to make a tourniquet, fool.
我知道很疼，可我得让你知道我是认真的
l know it hurts, but I had to make a point with you.
让我恼火的不是这个
That ain't what's pissing me off.
你冲我的车开枪才让我不爽
You shooting my van is what's pissing me off, man.
脑子让门夹了
What's wrong with you?
你是陆军游骑兵？
You Army Ranger, son?
下面的话你可要想好再说，欧巴桑
Be real careful of what you say next, pops.
在你开始侮辱我的部队之前先把子弹退膛
And be ready to empty that burner if you start shit- talking my battalion.
两肋插刀为兄弟
Never shall I fail my comrades.
身怀绝技气蔚然
Gallantly will I show the world that I am a specially selected soldier.
凭我一身好武艺
Energetically will I meet the enemies of my country.
御国杀敌过万千
l shall defeat them on the field of battle
只解沙场为国死
for I am better trained.
何须马革裹尸还
And I will fight with all my might.
汉尼拔·史密斯上校，第75兵团
Colonel Hannibal Smith. 75th Ranger Regiment.
佐治亚州贝宁军区，第4大队
4th Battalion. Fort Benning, Georgia.
我知道你也是，长官 大头，巴库斯下士
l know who you are, sir. Corporal B.A. Baracus.
我是说，我遭人暗算被开除之前是下士
l mean, it was till I was dishonorably discharged for some bullshit.
这可不是什么巧合，下士
l don't subscribe to coincidence, Corporal.
我深信，不管事情看起来多么偶然
l believe that, no matter how random things might appear,
背后总有原因的
there's still a plan.
我们把他喂狗了
We fed him to the dogs.
就像身处墨西哥的沙漠戈壁
That here in the middle of the Mexican desert,
我需要一位游骑兵搭档
when I needed him most,
他就会适时地出现一样
l'd find a fellow Ranger.
伙计
(SlGHS) Boy.
现在我要你帮我去救另一个
Now, I need your help to save another.
你倒霉了小子！
Bad news foryou today!
你的救兵，已经在一个小时之前
This rescue that's coming, we fed him to the Rottweilers
- 被我们喂狗了 - 你太天真了
- about an hour ago. - You know what's funny?
居然会以为已经抓住了我
ls that you actually believe that you got me.
居然会以为能杀掉我
(ON RADlO) You actually think you're gonna kill me.
还能开车吗？
Can you drive?
你就瞧好吧，长官
Better than anybody you've ever seen, sir.
之前没人知道你的老巢
Nobody knew where you were hiding...
可现在不同了，白痴
There was no intel...until now, asshole.
几分钟后，我就会开始享用冰镇啤酒
ln a few minutes I'm gonna be having a cold beer,
而你却会变成烧烤，保重吧，朋友
and you are gonna be on fire. Take care, my friend.
- 哥温，讷伊… - 不！
- Alpha, Mike... No!
…木阿
...Foxtrot.
猜猜看
Think about it.
滚…你…妈
Adiós, mother...
汉尼拔！
Hannibal!
你这是干吗？
What are you doing?
上车！
Get in!
大头，走
B.A., move.
太他妈操蛋了！
This is bullshit!
都去死吧！
Ahora, muerto!
停下！快停下！
Stop it! Please stop!
停！停！停！
Please stop! Stop it! Stop! Please stop!
感觉如何？
How's your day going?
要不你来尝尝这个
This is not going to taste good.
宝贝，我刚吐过
Baby, I just threw up.
我吃块口香糖再啵儿
Let me get some gum. Let me just get some gum.
都看见了吗？看见图克的表情了吗？
Did you see that? Did you see Tuco's face?
你们冲进来的时候，丫直接傻眼了！
When you came over, that was unbelievable!
- 说过多少遍了！ - 来得太是时候了
- How many times did I say it? - The timing was perfect.
- 说过多少遍了 - 真是太刺激了
- How many times did I say it, Face? - lt was so beautiful.
- 我说过不要一个人来抓图克 - 什么？
- I told you not to take down Tuco alone. - What?
那你…
Well, you...
好吧，对不起
You know what? I'm sorry.
很遗憾我没熟读“汉尼拔战斗攻略”
I'm sorry I didn't have the Hannibal Smith How- to Manual.
- 可我得行动啊 - 就像困在轮胎里行动
- Okay? I had to move. - And that move snowballs, Face.
你差点把小命丢掉
You almost got yourself killed.
多谢，我叫贝克
Which almost got me killed and almost got him killed.
头脑简单
Five-year-old.
你的表情就像别人欠你很多钱似的
You look like you got a real bad attitude.
你他妈…
What?
敢情你的车没被枪打？
Did I shoot up your van?
你最爱的T恤没被人穿？
Am I wearing your favorite shirt?
这就是你最喜欢的T恤？
This is your favorite shirt?
没错，小白脸，它就是
Yeah, pretty boy, that's my favorite shirt.
这个枪伤也是因为我喽？
Did you get shot for me, too?
- 车也被劫了 - 被我
- And carjacked. - By me.
等等，他居然还让当司机？
(CHUCKLES) Wait, and he still got you to drive?
谢谢你——贝克
Thank you. Peck.
巴库斯——别见外
Baracus. lt's all good.
听着，小帅，这就是不做好部署的下场
See, Face, this is what happens when we forget about plans
像群无头苍蝇
and just fire blind.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
抱歉我有常人的情感
I'm so sorry that I have feelings for a human being,
- 会坠入爱河 - 爱河？
- that I fell in love. - Love?
等等，3周前那个克罗地亚小姐是怎么回事？
Wait a minute. What about Miss Croatia three weeks ago?
一夜情而已
Rescue sex.
我刚才只是想救她
l was just trying to save her.
- 救她？ - 没错
- Save her? - Yeah.
救她？怎么救？
Save her? How?
拜托，下次有事跟我先商量，小帅
Please, do share with us your plan, Face.
好吧，我的确没想到这一点
Okay, I hadn't thought about that yet.
没错，可我得想到
Exactly. I had to.
她的机票
Her plane ticket.
工作签证和新护照
Her work visa and her new passport.
别以为我这么做是为了她
And don't bullshit me that this was about her, Face.
这都是为了图克的事
This was all about Tuco.
还有个弹夹吗？
Do you have a mag?
- 迈克 - 老大，最近好吗？
- Mike. - Boss man. How the hell are you?
- 还在干那个破差事吗？ - 很不幸，是的
- Still chewing the same dirt? - I am, unfortunately.
- 还在美丽的墨西哥 - 很好
- And out here in lovely Mexico. - Good.
- 我要的东西弄来了吗？ - 给你找了个送外卖的大鸟
- So what have you got for me? - I got a fast bird doing pizza runs.
- 电台呼号是“战斧” - 战斧，不错
- The call sign is "Hatchet." - Hatchet. Okay.
上天入地任你处置
And that is whatever you want it to be.
给你的
This is yours.
墨西哥人很快就会追来
General, may I remind you, they don't take to the gringos.
我欠你个人情
l owe you one, okay?
- 欠债从来不还是吧？ - 过几年再说
- Let's not wait till Bragg again, huh? - Three years.
- 小帅到哪儿都不忘泡妞 - 大头，怎么？
And the kid. Still you and the chicks. - B.A. What?
我怎么忍心把我的宝贝儿就这么丢下？
How am I gonna just leave my girl like this, after all that?
为了找她回来我可费了不少劲
l had to fight to get her back.
把钥匙留下，我们会回来找她的
Leave the keys and we'll come back for her. Come on.
太寒酸了
Looking shabby.
- 这次又要干什么，老弟？ - 只要看见活的就开枪，懂吗？
- What is the deal, brother? - Shoot anything that moves, okay?
- 这可比哥伦比亚还糟糕 - 我了解图克，老弟
- This is worse than Colombia. - I know Tuco, man.
放心吧，我会把她送到一个安全的地方
Don't worry about it. l'll take her to war college in Saint Tropez.
到时把电话给你，不用担心
l'll get you all their numbers, so don't worry about it.
- 小帅，照顾好大头 - 好，没问题
- Face, look after the Corporal. - Yeah. Okay.
搞了一身汽油味，刚才一定很刺激
And you're covered in gas, which I think is interesting.
去缝合一下伤口，下士
Find a treatment room, Corporal.
要快，我去找飞行员
Make it quick. I'm gonna find our pilot.
嘿
Hey.
嘿，大夫，能给一个负伤老兵看看吗？
Hey, Doc, you got a second for a wounded vet?
小飞侠
默多克上尉
他是个获勋无数的飞行员
Highly decorated combat pilot.
要是问他自己，他会说全世界也没人比得上他
You ask him, he thinks he's the best in the world.
可他总是疯疯癫癫
But he's a functioning lunatic.
上星期还试图用起搏器偷救护车逃跑
Last week he tried to escape by jump- starting an ambulance.
预备
Clear.
我靠！
Damn it!
就他了
My kind of guy.
差点就把你的纹身弄花了
lt almost hit your tattoo there.
有人看见默多克先生吗？
Has anyone seen Mr. Murdock?
- 游骑兵图徽 - 默多克先生？
- The old Ranger tat. Mr. Murdock?
我要是说我也有一个，你会不会觉得我疯了？
Would you think I was crazy if I told you I had one of these?
你的眼神不大对劲，老兄
Something wrong with your eyes, man.
- 默多克先生？ - 没看见在手术吗，护士
- Mr. Murdock? - Not while I'm operating, nurse.
- 现在不行 - 你怎么不在病房呆着？
- Not now. - Why are you off the ward?
是不是汽油？你带进来的？
ls that gas? ls that you?
- 我闻见汽油味了 - 你说什么？病房？
- I smell gas. - What do you mean, "ward"?
- 什么病房？ - 他是这里的病人
- What ward? - This man is a patient here.
是不是你？别听她的，她疯了
ls this you? Don't listen to her, she's crazy.
实话告诉你吧 我是约翰·霍普金斯大学来的实习医生
Honestly, I'm a practicing doctor at Johns Hopkins University.
- 你让他缝合成闪电的形状了？ - 我没要什么闪电
- Did you ask him to do a lightning bolt? - I asked for no lightning bolt.
- 我去叫保安 - 这个白痴想干什么？
- I'm calling security. What's wrong with this fool?
- 他是疯子？ - 就是你！
- ls he crazy? - lt is you.
- 你着火了，哥们 - 什么？怎么了？
- You on fire, man. - What? What's that?
- 真他妈的… - 老天！
- What the... - Oh, Jesus!
- 游骑兵，我喜欢你们！ - 你疯了吗？
- You Rangers. I like you! - Are you crazy?
嘿！嘿！怎么了？
- Hey! Hey, come on!
下士，退后！
Corporal, off. Back off!
这里是医院
This is a hospital.
- 两位都见过默多克先生 - 见过？
- Everybody's met Mr. Murdock. Met him?
他把我胳膊点着了
He lit my arm on fire.
还在我胳膊上缝了条闪电
He stitched a lightning bolt in mine, man.
看着我，小子
Look at me, son.
听说你是个很棒的直升机飞行员
I'm told you're a hell of a chopper pilot.
是最棒的，长官
The best, sir.
我才不会坐这个疯子的飞机
I'm not getting on a chopper with this nut job.
太棒了…他是不是你的又一个棋子？
Yeah, that's a good... ls he another one of your projects?
我是货真价实的军人，游骑兵，伙计
I'm a real soldier. I'm a Ranger, baby.
我很担心！
I'm worried!
我是游骑兵，长官
I'm a Ranger, sir.
我已经很满意了
That's good enough for me.
你现在我们征召了
You have been released into our care
- 官复原职，上尉 - 我可是一点都没觉得满意
- and reinstated, Captain. - I'm not even close to good with that.
多谢，长官
Thank you, sir.
我们现在就出发
Let's get the hell out of here.
我那婀娜动人锈迹斑斑的宝贝
(lN BRlTlSH ACCENT) You gorgeous old rust bucket, you.
想老爸了吗？
Did you miss your daddy?
小帅，一个周密计划的关键是什么？
Face, what's the most important part of a well- oiled plan?
总是先于敌人一步
To be one step ahead of the enemy,
- 而不是被他们追着跑 - 谁说我们要逃跑了？
- not to be running away from him. - Who says we're running?
什么？要我们跟着一个精神病
What, we're going to go in this dinosaur
- 坐进这堆废铁？ - 没错
- with this freak show? - Yep.
宝贝，带着老爸去兜风，去兜风吧
(SlNGlNG) You spin me right round, baby Right round
- 旋翼正常，长官 - 这家伙是谁？
- Rotors are good, sir. - Who is this guy?
快，大家快！
Come on! Let's go!
把美国佬都干掉！
We've got gringos to kill!
默多克，快把这怪物飞起来
Murdock, get this thing in the air.
坐稳了，帅哥们！
Hold on, boys!
我要试一个动画片里看过的动作
I'm gonna try something I saw in a cartoon once.
别再飞沫子了，赶紧起飞！
What you talking about cartoons for? Get us the hell out of here!
六点钟方向有架武装直升机
We got a hot chopper to your six.
我会挡子弹，我们刀枪不入
I'm blocking bullets. We're bulletproof.
我们刀枪不入，伙计们！
We're bulletproof, boys!
哦，抬头！
Oh, heads up.
我看见你们了，美国佬！
l see you, gringo!
你砸扁了我的车，我跟你没完，混蛋！
You pancaked my van! I'm gonna kill you, fool!
谁让你违章停车的，那可是残疾人专区
You can't park there. That's a handicap zone.
- 早就知道你是个疯子！ - 这下完蛋了
- I knew you was crazy! I knew... - This is a mistake.
开火！开火！开火！
Fire! Fire! Fire!
把他们打烂
Blow them out of the sky.
我还从来没这么飞过！
l've never tried this before!
都看见了吧？
Did you see that?
看见那架直升机转圈了吗？
Did you see how he turned the helicopter?
再没有比空空对战更刺激的了，对吗，伙计们？
Whoa! There's nothing like some good air- to- air combat, eh, boys?
别看我，看前面！
Don't look at me! Look there!
他们只剩下热追踪导弹了
He's only got heat seekers left.
上尉，离开这鬼地方
Captain, get us out of here.
坐稳了，来个刺激的！
Hold on, this could get ugly!
好样的！来吧宝贝，爬升！
Here we go! Come on, baby, climb!
发射导弹
Fire the missiles.
哇！导弹！快啊！快啊！
Whoa! Missiles! Come on, come on.
对付热追踪的方法就是
(lN BRlTlSH ACCENT) That's how we deal with heat seekers, chaps.
凉快会儿！
We go cold.
真该死
What the hell?
小帅，把他拉上来！
- Face, get him in here!
该死！该死！
Holy, shit! Oh, shit!
抓住了！
Got him!
重启！快重启！
Restart. Restart.
把门关上！
Close the door!
我知道你们是空军游骑兵，可这也太鬼扯了！
l know you're Airborne Rangers, but that was ridiculous!
马上就没事了
You're gonna be okay.
头儿，我们是要杀了图克，而不是被他杀掉！
Boss, the idea is to kill Tuco, not the other way around!
只比敌人领先一步可不够
One step ahead of the game isn't a plan, kid.
要领先很多步
Two to three steps ahead.
出其不意攻其无备
Beating an enemy's move before it's even made.
才是王道！
That's a plan.
战斧，战斧，锁定我的位置
Hatchet, Hatchet, lock on my LC.
图克将军，你未经授权擅自挑起
General Tuco, you are currently engaged
针对美国军事人员的战斗
in unauthorized warfare on United States military personnel.
不不不不不！是你先挑起的！
No, no, no, no, no, no, no! You engaged me.
重复
Repeat.
你未经授权擅自挑起针对美国军事人员的战斗
You are engaged in unauthorized warfare on United States military personnel.
并已侵入美国领空
Over United States air space.
- 什么？ - 哥温，讷伊…
- What? - Alpha, Mike...
- 木阿！ …木阿！
- Foxtrot! - ...Foxtrot!
- 意思是：滚你妈… - 哦，不！
- ln other words, Adiós, mother... - Oh, no.
耶！
Yeah!
好样的，上尉
Well done, Captain.
- 太帅了！ - 帅个屁！
- That was awesome. - That wasn't awesome.
- 你是个天才！ - 我再也不坐这怪物了！
- You are a genius! - I'm never flying again in this thing!
当初真不应该怀疑你，头儿！
l never should have doubted you, boss!
姜还是老的辣，小伙
There's a plan in everything, kid.
这就叫老谋深算
And I love it when a plan comes together.
天龙特攻队
8 年…
…80项出色任务后
“猎首”行动基地
伊拉克撤军前夕
火药烧烤，趣味无穷
Gunpowder cooking. Nothing like it.
小帅，油烧还是核爆？
Face, you want it napalmed or nuked?
核爆吧
Nuke it.
- 那就核爆！ - 嗯呢！
- Nuke it! - Mmm- hmm.
默多克，使劲烤
Murdock, burn the hell out of it,
往死里烤
like it was damned.
不如把基地都烤掉
Burn the whole place down, buddy.
- 要加秘制酱料吗？ - 不不不，别再给我加防冻液了
You want secret sauce? - No, no, no. None of that anti- freeze.
小点声，你疯了，让别人都听见了
The secret's out. You crazy. Everybody knows.
天底下也只有你用防冻液做卤汁，默多克
No one can do an anti- freeze marinade like you can, Murdock.
我上次差点吃成脑残
But I got a little Bell's palsy last time I ate that.
只是偏瘫而已，拜托，这点胆量都没有
lt's only partial paralysis. Come on, take it like a man.
是的，长官，我已经在谈了
Yes, sir. I'm having that conversation right now.
我们能办妥的，包在我身上，长官
We will enforce that. l've got it well in hand, sir.
我猜你也不想让我半瘫在战场上吧，老兄
l don't think you want me to be in the field partially paralyzed, bud.
美女耶
Visitors.
没错
Yeah.
喔，我有点招架不住了，这次不撒谎了
Wow, I'm a little taken aback. I'm not gonna lie.
中尉
Lieutenant.
哦，抱歉，我是不是也应该叫你中尉？
Oh, I'm sorry, am I supposed to call you Lieutenant back?
不，你得叫上尉
No, you're supposed to call me Captain.
上尉，上尉？
Captain. Captain?
没错
That's right.
上尉大人，瞧瞧啊，哇
Captain Crunch. Look at you. Wow.
我猜是因为你不要孩子不要家庭
So, I guess you said no to the kids, no to the family.
他们就让你平步青云了对吗？
Just no ladder you can't climb, huh?
不不，亲爱的，我只是不要你
No, no, honey, I just said no to you.
哈罗，我叫珀西
Hello. My name's Percy.
想来点猪肉吗？
Would you like some pork?
要是我把你的手拧断，你还能耍花样吗？
lf I broke every bone in your hand, could you still do that?
太疯狂了，3年了吧？
This is crazy. Three years?
我们都3年不见了
We haven't seen each other for three years,
刚见面就讨论这个？
this is what we're gonna talk about?
那你想讨论什么？
What would you like to discuss?
我的摇滚唱片是不是你拿走的？
Did you take my Steely Dan CD?
别指望我回答这种问题
I'm not even going to respond to that.
我们一起听过好多遍呢
We listened to it, like, nine times in a row.
还一起喝低劣的红酒，你忘了吗？
We were drinking that crappy cabernet. You remember that?
我们还一起做别的事，做什么来着？
We were doing something else. What were we doing?
你还记得那事吗？在床上做的？
Do you remember what it was we were doing? lt was in a bedroom.
不记得了？
You don't remember?
我唯一记得的就是离你而去
The only thing I remember is leaving.
那是关于你的最美回忆
Which is my fondest memory of you.
哥几个是最棒的，少惹麻烦，记住了吗？
You guys are the best. Stay out of trouble, you hear me?
保重，好的，多谢
Take care. Yes. Thank you.
头盔戴好
Keep that on.
少校，我叫林奇，中情局探员
Colonel, my name is Lynch, I'm with Central lntelligence.
第一次沙漠风暴中我认识一个叫林奇的孙子
l knew a company man named Lynch back in the first Desert Storm.
在我之前也有很多林奇
Yeah, I come from a long line of Lynches.
你有没有想过也许没人相信中情局的人
You ever stop to consider that maybe the reason nobody trusts the ClA
就是因为他们从来不用真名实姓？
is because nobody knows your real names?
有何贵干，林奇先生？
What can I do for you, Mr. Lynch?
帮我阻止一股萨达姆的旧党
l need you to help me to stop Saddam's former flunkies
他们要在未来30小时窃取超过10亿美金
from stealing over a billion dollars in the next 30 hours.
听着，美国本土外唯一一座能造美元的造币厂
Now, the only mint outside of the U.S. capable of printing our money
位于伊朗
belonged to the Shah of lran.
于两伊战争期间失窃
During the lran- lraq War, it went missing.
有人怀疑是萨达姆干的
Rumor was, Saddam had stolen it.
沙漠风暴中我们又夺了回来
And we stole it back during Desert Storm.
只是金属电板不见了
Well, you didn't get the engraving plates.
小题大做
lt didn't matter.
他们不至于为了几块面板建座造币厂吧
They would have had to rebuild a mint just to print those bills.
没错，长官
Well, sir,
我们谈话的时候就在建
it's happening as we speak.
那帮土匪抢了伊拉克国家造币厂的机器
Fedayeen thugs have seized what's left of the lraqi National Mint
打算印制数十亿未经备案的美钞
to run off billions of dollars in unbacked American currency.
他们打算如何把电板和这么多钱
How are they planning on moving the plates and a billion dollars
- 运出巴格达？ - 武装运钞车
- out of Baghdad? - Armored convoy,
前伊拉克突击队员负责押解
manned with former lraqi spec ops.
全是势如闪电、百步穿杨的主儿
You know, high speed, shoot- to- kill types.
听听你的打算？
So how do you plan on stopping them?
听着，传言萨达姆的愚忠正谋划
Listen, there's some rumors about some top- secret plates
把一批绝密电板偷运出巴格达
being smuggled out of the city by Saddam loyalists.
这事你听说了吗？
Do you know anything about this?
警告你，要是敢打这几块电板的主意
Seriously, if you're going to make a play for these plates,
别怪我不客气
I'm waving you off right now.
因为这是我的职责，所以只有我能管
'Cause it's my responsibility and it's my ass.
我是认真的
I'm serious.
- 小帅？ - 嗯哼？
- Face? - Mmm- hmm.
想上军事法庭吗？
l will court- martial you.
- 哇！好吧 - 嘿
- Whoo! Okay. - Hey.
给我听清楚
Get the memo.
转告你亲爱的史密斯上校，离巴格达远点
Tell your beloved Colonel Smith and stay the hell out of Baghdad.
知道吗
You know,
你一去不返，我可一直都在等待
you never came back. I thought you were gonna come back.
我现在不是回来了吗
Well, this is me, coming back.
你真相信这几个傻鸟不会惹事？
You think those clowns can really pull this off?
听着听着，这话我绝不会当面说
Listen, listen, I would never tell him this,
但他们的确是所有四人特攻队里面最出色的
but they are the best clandestine unit in the four branches,
专干别人干不了的活儿
and they specialize in the ridiculous.
我去找剩下的人
Shadow Peck and the rest of them.
- 把他们都给我盯死 - 是，长官
- Do not let them out of your sight. - Yes, ma'am.
- “diablo”是不是恶魔的意思？ - 没错，老兄
- Doesn't diablo mean "devil"? - Yeah, man.
该死，汉尼拔，你要我怎么办？
God damn it, Hannibal, what do you want me to do?
拉塞尔·莫里森将军  指挥中心
这次行动要是归我指挥，你要想接
lf this were my operation and you wanted it,
- 就只管接手 - 可你却交给暮色森林
- you would have the mission. - You let Black Forest deploy on this,
这可是国际事件，我保证
and it's an international incident, I promise you.
他们都算不得军人
They're not soldiers.
只是一群滥杀无辜的纨绔子弟
They're frat boys with trigger fingers.
- 地面部队由谁指挥？ - 布洛克·派克
- Who's running the ground team? - Brock Pike.
派克
Pike.
他就是个土匪，太搞笑了吧，拜托
He's a thug. He's a cartoon character. Come on.
汉尼拔，这是上头的意思，让你
Hannibal, we have been ordered, ordered, mind you,
别掺和巴格达的事
to stay out of Baghdad.
- 谈话到此结束 - 将军
- Cut, dried, the end. General,
或许还有商量的余地，不是吗？
we should find him a little wiggle room, don't you think?
听着，我认识中情局另一个叫林奇的白痴
You know, I knew another Lynch, a ClA stooge.
1968年去过老挝
Stationed in Laos, '68.
- 不认识 - 你确定？
- No relation. - Are you sure?
因为我看你们是一路货色
'Cause you remind me of him.
几个小时后我要赶到喀布尔
I'm due in Kabul in a few hours.
48小时后回来，我希望到时已经谈妥
l'll be back here in 48. I'm assuming we're green and go.
否则就给我消息
Notify me otherwise.
在司令部还穿防弹衣
He's wearing body armor in the HQ.
现在能看出中情局都是什么德性了吧
And that should tell you everything you need to know about the ClA.
拉塞尔，走出这里之前我还想问你最后一遍
Russ, let's do some good on the way out the door here.
这次任务非同小可
Those plates are gonna do all kinds of damage.
还是让我去吧
Let me go get them.
算了，汉尼拔，离这事远点
Forget about it, Hannibal. Steer clear of this one.
越远越好
Well clear of it.
萨德尔这个地方历来兵荒马乱
This is a gauntlet run right through the heart of Sadr City.
萨达姆已经够疯狂了吧
Saddam Hussein was a certifiable madman,
即便是他这种人
but even he wasn't crazy enough
30年来也从未踏足此地
to go into that place more than once in 30 years.
一周前我们从那里撤出的时候已经是满目疮痍了
We pulled out of there a week ago and already it's the Wild West.
你的话里透着一股忧虑
(CHUCKLES) You actually sound worried.
- 你透着一种被冒犯的感觉 - 就是
- And you actually seem offended. - Yeah.
我想要你知道不是不重用你
Well, this isn't about you losing a step now.
必须跟你说清楚
l want you to know that.
- 嘿 - 嘿
- Hey. - Hey.
我现在比刚认识你的时候要强得多
I'm 1 0 times the man I was when you met me.
- 嗯哼 - 也快的多
- Uh- huh. - And twice as fast.
头儿
Russ,
我和兄弟们肯定能全身而退
the boys and I can get this done, minus the bloodshed.
这次任务非同小可
Those plates can do all kinds of damage.
别逼我求你
Don't make me beg.
我也不想你求我，汉尼拔
l'd hate to see you beg, Hannibal.
你我都是老相识了
You've been my friend for a long time.
还有
More importantly,
你和你的弟兄
you and those boys have possibly been
可是我手下最得意的王牌
the most valuable military asset I have ever had at my disposal.
你居然还让我别逼你求我
Now, you asked me not to make you beg.
我现在就在求你
Right now, I'm begging you.
汉尼拔，求你了，这次就放手吧
Hannibal, please, let this one go.
头儿，这次任务真的儿戏不得 不能交给一群白痴去做
Russ, this is too big an enterprise. We can't let these bozos do this.
真的儿戏不得
lt's way too big.
无论有没有我的祝愿，你都会去做？
And you'd do it with or without my blessing?
不，那不会
No, that I wouldn't.
我需要你的祝愿
l need your blessing.
不知道这算不算是祝愿
I'm not so sure that it is a blessing.
祝你们好运，朋友
Good hunting, my friend.
谢谢
Thank you.
跟老家伙谈的如何？
How'd it go with the old man?
老顽固一个，你手里拿的什么？
Same old, same old. What you got there?
新宝贝的照片
Pictures of my new baby.
快来看啊，这是谁的啊？
Oh, look at her. Who's a proud papa?
这些是默多克找到的跟我那辆车最接近的了
These pictures are the closest Murdock gets to that van.
我一回洛杉矶立马到手
lt's ready for me when I go back to LA.
听着，大头，我们这次要多待几天了
Listen, B.A., we're extending our stay a little bit.
我们要返回巴格达
We're going back into Baghdad.
不是命令我们离巴格达远点吗
l thought we was ordered to stay out of Baghdad.
- 没错，可我… - 史密斯
- That's true, but I'm... Smith.
- 派克 - 听说你和你的马仔
- Pike. - I understand you and your grunts
在抢我的饭碗，所以我很不爽
are now stealing my gigs. I don't like that.
你们暮色森林的大人物应该忙于
l figured you Black Forest guys would be busy
推翻民主建立独裁才对啊
installing a dictatorship or overthrowing a democracy somewhere.
我们周末不干活，这都是小菜一碟，欧巴桑
lt's still the weekend, yet. That's nine- to- five stuff, pops.
看看你们的德性
Look at you clowns.
哪点像军人
You're not soldiers.
简直就是穿着保罗衫的刺客
You're assassins in polo shirts.
我们一星期能干完的活，你们要磨上一年
We'll make in a week what you guys make in a year.
钱买不来胆子，小子
Cash don't buy guts, kid,
也买不来脑子
or brains.
可惜你两样都缺
And you're short on both.
这是莫里森的地盘，赶紧给我滚
This is Morrison's base. Bug out of my op.
他们允许你在军营里穿这个，大头？
They make you wear the yellow shirt there, B.A.?
“大头”是头大无脑的意思吗？
What's that stand for, "Barely Able"?
滚一边去，白痴
Get out of my way, punk.
嘿，别惹他们
Hey, don't sweat them.
我们还要他们帮忙呢，帮大忙
They might have just done us a favor. A big one.
我查查，我们还有辆中型坦克
Let me see, we got one medium tank left.
我说过，她回来一定有原因的
I'm telling you, there's a reason she came back.
小帅，听我的，死心吧
Face, I told you, forget about her.
以这种女人的野心…
The levels of ambition on this woman...
我再也不坐会飞的玩意儿了，汉尼拔
l ain't stepping foot in any type of aircraft, Hannibal.
滑翔机、纸飞机、便携式…
No gliders, paper planes, ultra- lights.
- 你就忘不了这点陈芝麻烂谷子吗？ - 不能
- You ever gonna let me live that down? - No.
墨西哥的事都过去多久了，我可是救了你一命
Mexico was a long time ago, and I saved your life.
那我没在医院里把你捶扁，你是不是该谢我呢？
How about thanking me for not whooping your ass at the hospital?
碰见你以前我还是个空军游骑兵
l was an Airborne Ranger until I met you.
当时你却吓得像只…
And you chickened out just like...
- 263次跳伞记录 - 你只需要说声谢谢就够了
- 263 jumps. - Just a thank- you would have been nice.
而坐了一次你的直升机就全毁了
And one helicopter ride with you screws it up.
空军游骑兵怕坐飞机，够可怜吧！
Airborne Ranger with a fear of flying. Like a punk!
大头，我最后声明一次，一旦得手
B.A., for the last time, nobody leaves the truck
谁也不离开货车，可以吗？
once we take it over. Okay?
我表弟有次带我去一个摇滚派对
My cousin takes me to this party where this amazing cover band
他们演奏了林昂内尔·里奇的《哈罗》 （代表作：Say You, Say Me）
does this trash metal version of Hello by Lionel Richie.
- 是的 - 是这么唱的…
- Yeah. - Yeah. lt goes...
“哈罗，你是不是在寻觅…”
(SlNGlNG) Hello, is it me you're looking for?
伙计们，他们在里面呆多久了？
Guys, how long have they been in there?
- 大概3小时 - 3小时
- About three hours. - Three hours.
3个小时？
Three hours?
他们都在里面呆3小时了？从没出来过？
They've been in there for three hours? They haven't come out at all?
没人出来上厕所什么的吗？
No one came out to take a leak, nothing?
- 没 - 没有
- No. - Nope.
可我刚来3秒钟就发现事情不对劲
l've been here for three seconds and that sounds odd to me.
我们一直盯着他们帐篷呢
l've been watching that tent like a hawk.
是吗？我怎么看着像是屁股坐得稳稳的吃调味饭呢
Really? lt looks like you're eating some risotto and sitting on your ass.
我不知道，我想来点汤呢
l don't know. I wanted the soup.
- 我没在吃调味饭，我在… - 这个不叫调味饭
- I wasn't eating risotto. I had... - lt's not risotto.
伙计们
Yeah, boys.
耶，他想打架是吗？
Yeah, he wants to fight, doesn't he?
我靠，不是吧，还给我们叫了小姐？
Damn, this is awesome. They got us a stripper, too.
这马子条儿太正了，我喜欢
You got that hot enlisted look. Me likey.
别逼我把你们全打趴下，他们人呢？
Before I throw you in the stockade, where are they?
他们没说去哪儿…上尉！
They didn't tell us... Captain.
他们只留下一箱啤酒，每人给了50块钱
They just gave us a case of beer and 50 bucks apiece.
给了我100块
(CHUCKLES) I got a hundred.
哦，真的吗？
Oh, did you get a hundred?
这个假发可不可以带走？
You think we get to keep the hair?
时间、地点、部署
Staging, movement, action plan.
好好拜读一下
There's a nice read for you.
见鬼，汉尼拔，你太有才了
(LAUGHlNG) Hell, yeah, Hannibal. This is it right here.
这简直是鬼扯
This is bat- shit insane.
- 完美无瑕 - 胆大妄为啊，头儿
- lt's perfect. - This is beyond nuts, boss.
好戏在后头
lt gets better.
大头，去按你的身材弄一块铁板做滑板
B.A., you'll need a piece of contoured metal to make a skid plate.
走了，傻帽
(WHlSPERlNG) Let's go, fool.
默多克，去找块车用电池
Murdock, we'll need a car battery, too.
暮色森林那边应该有搞头
See if the boys at Black Forest can help us out.
记者证也是必须的
Press credentials, we need them.
去新闻中心转转，看有什么收获
Hit the media tent and see what's lying around.
对不起，朋友，我看你把
Sorry, my friend, I see you've put
南非电视台的话筒放在最下面
the South African microphone at the bottom.
不能总把CNN放在最上面
You can't always put the CNN on top.
大兵，这有两个话筒，我不清楚是不是…
Private, there are two mics. I don't know if there is something...
l was a moving man in my younger days
默多克，还需要一台摄像机
Murdock, we need a news camera.
你去想想办法
See what you can do.
抱歉，抱歉，抱歉
All right, sorry. Sorry. Sorry.
你好，我…
Hello. I'm...
我爱上你了
I'm in love with you.
听着，我们正在进行一项调查问卷
Listen, we're doing a preliminary poll of...
我们说什么来着？关于撤军是吧
What are we talking about? Of the pull- out.
还需要安全气囊，越多越好
We're gonna need airbags, lots of them.
- 你是哪家媒体的，甜心？ - 《世界报》
- What bureau are you with, darling? - Le Monde.
你是法国人？
Are you French?
你好，我是帕克将军，我需要…
Hello, this is General Parker. I need...
好吧，你来说
Okay. lt's for you.
傻鸟，发动空袭的电话你还是自己打吧
Hey, fool, you need to call an air strike on yourself.
- 我们还要聊会儿，伙计，待会见 - 不，我们应该一起走
- We're good, mate. l'll meet you. - No, I think we need to get going now.
你得明白我在说什么
You need to understand what I'm telling you right now.
大头，我们需要一块磁铁
B.A., we're gonna need a magnet.
- 耶！ - 很强大！
- Yeah! - A powerful one.
有人看过“蓝衣军团”吗？ （《勇敢的心》）
You ever seen Blue Man Group?
剩下的我去找
l'll pick up the rest.
我现在要走了
I'm just gonna go for it.
哦啦啦
Ooh, la, la.
给你一次机会
(lN SCOTTlSH ACCENT) What would you give for one chance
回到战场告诉我们的敌人
to come back here and tell our enemies
他们可以夺走我们的生命
that they may take our lives,
但夺不走我们的自由！
but they'll never take our freedom!
准备好了吗？
Ready to go downtown?
祝你们好运
Good luck tomorrow.
- 谢谢 - 把他们都干掉！
- Thank you. - Give 'em hell.
莫里森将军，汉尼拔·史密斯在哪？
General Morrison, where the hell is Hannibal Smith?
上尉，我建议你更改一下说话的语气.
Captain, you would do well to revise your tone and readdress me.
将军，我有国防部的命令，不受你指挥
General, I have authority under DClS that supersedes your command,
再问一遍，不要让我们双方都为难
so last time, before this becomes embarrassing for the both of us,
汉尼拔去了哪里？
where is Hannibal Smith?
你先出去一下，上校
Would you excuse us, General?
上尉，在从军的40年里
Captain, in nearly 40 years of being in this army,
我学会了在下属面前
l have learned to control my temper
控制自己的情绪和语调
and my voice when in the presence of a subordinate officer
而你，就目前而言，却他妈的有点失去理智
who, for at least the time being, seems to have lost her goddamn mind.
要是我没说错的话
Now, it is my understanding
现在是你有求于我对吗？
that you have a question for me. ls that correct?
是的，长官
You are correct, sir.
那就等你记起自己的身份
Then when you are prepared to remember that you are still an officer
是个穿着便装的美国陆军一员
in the United States Army, in spite of your civilian attire,
并且准备好按军队的规矩提问的时候
and are ready to present that question in a military fashion,
再来跟我讨论吧
then perhaps we could get somewhere with this discussion.
如果你已经把特攻队派往巴格达，不管什么理由
lf you have sent an Alpha Team into Baghdad for any reason whatsoever,
都是对国防部命令的直接违抗
that is a direct violation of a DoD order.
好吧，既然你是这种态度
Well, and as much as you have this kind of knowledge,
就不要打算从我这里问走一个字
l can't help wondering why it is that you need to ask anything of me.
我就当你默认了，长官
l will take that as your confirmation, sir.
他们3小时后开始行动
They go mobile in three hours.
电板和现金
The plates and over a billion dollars
将会装在一辆拖车上的集装箱里
will be loaded into the back of a semi at the mint.
他们行驶4.6英里之后到达大桥
They're overland for exactly 4.6 miles before they reach the bridge.
大桥是机会，而且稍纵即逝
That's our window, and it closes fast.
一有风吹草动，这帮人就会大开杀戒
These guys will go weapons hot at the first whisper of trouble.
小帅，你从酒店地下进入
Face, your point of entry is under the hotel.
那里到时会被外国记者和保安围的水泄不通
lt'll be packed with foreign press and private security.
大头，你在小巷里计时待命
B.A., you're in this alleyway on a stopwatch.
摩托车至少要V2引擎
Make sure the bike has V- tins or better.
我的家伙可是超宝马赛奔驰
l got something a whole lot better than that.
我干什么，头儿？
- Bam! - What about me, boss man?
我有架小型直升机停在附近
l had a little helicopter here someplace.
能飞翻转吗？空中急停呢？
You got some barrel rolls Some mid- air stalls?
我都等不及又一次空中历险了
I'm looking for my next near- death experience.
这次你只做空中支援，上尉
Only air support this time, Captain,
但下次保证让你过足瘾
but l'll get you in on the next one. I promise.
大头，你在6:30准时出发
B.A., I need you to pop that clutch at 0630.
这是我吗？
ls that me?
差点忘了，自己是在伊拉克的下水道里 谢谢了头儿！
Oh, no, I forgot. I'm in an lraqi sewer. Thanks, boss!
时间就是一切，小帅
Timing is everything, Face.
一定要眼疾手快
This is all about the bull's- eyes.
还用说
Why not?
然后你从拖车底下把身后的尾巴统统清掉
From under the semi, you'll take out the truck directly behind you.
嗯？
Huh?
到时这些人会上来收拾你，小帅
Now, these guys are gonna be onto you, Face.
大头，这时就该你出场了
B.A., that's your cue for throttle.
过马路之前记得看清两边
Be sure to look both ways before crossing.
也要记得把油箱加满
And have a nice full tank of gas.
车上肯定有重兵把守
You'll have multiple hostiles on board, B.A.
把他们统统消灭
Escort them from the premises.
至于其他残兵剩勇，不用担心，交给我打理
lf any stragglers sneak up behind, don't worry, I got your back.
上来吧，小子
Gotcha, kid.
好样的
Attaboy.
听起来是不错，可我还是不清楚到底怎么逃出巴格达
That's all fine in theory, but I still don't see how we get out of Baghdad.
我清楚
l do.
大头，右转！
B.A. ! Hang a right!
没问题，坐稳了！
All right! Hang on!
- 小心！小心！ - 趴下！
Watch out! Watch out! - Heads down!
干的漂亮，大头！
Oh! Nice one, B.A. !
小帅，准备气囊！
Face, get the airbags!
记得把锁扣绑结实！
Gotta make sure this thing stays locked for later!
漂亮！
Beautiful!
1、2、3！
One, two, three.
嘿，头儿，气囊受到撞击就能弹开对吧？
Hey, boss, airbags do deploy on impact, right?
大头，进集装箱
B.A., get in the container.
当心身后！
Contact, rear!
妈的！
Shit!
瞧，就是这个让我不放心！
See, this is the part of the plan I don't trust!
别害怕，绳子足够结实！
Don't worry, Face! The rope will hold!
我要是害怕早钻进集装箱了！
lf I was worried, l'd be nailing myself to the container right now!
抓牢了，小子！
Hang on, boys!
砰砰！来啊！全变烤猪！
Bam! Come on! I smoked you!
大伙儿都看见了吗？
(ON RADlO) You boys see that down there?
默多克，你个傻帽来干吗？
Murdock? What is that fool doing here?
别把我关在这，我不跟你们玩儿了！
Don't lock me in here. I ain't playing with y'all!
嘿，头儿，你们在游乐场玩过
Hey, boss, you ever play that game at the fun fair
铁爪取物的游戏吗？
where you try to pick up a stuffed animal with the claw?
跟这个太像了
This is a lot like that.
在这儿
That's it!
你们把它锁上了？
Did you lock this?
锁上了，是不是？
You locked it, didn't you?
汉尼拔，把门打开，快！
Hannibal, open this door right now, man!
真他妈…你们要把这东西吊起来？
What the... Are you hooking this thing?
- 用直升机把它吊走？ - 起飞了
- You hooking this up to a helicopter? - I got you.
这他妈的是在干什么？你们疯了是吗！
What the hell's going on? You ain't that crazy!
别跟我说又上天了！老子要杀了你们！
Tell me we ain't flying! I'm gonna kill you, fool!
- 头儿，博斯克在里面？ - 放我出去！
- Boss, is that Bosco? - Get me out of here!
- 不妙！ - 放我出去！
- That's not good. - Let me out of here!
不妙！他发怒了！
That's not good. He is not happy.
林奇探员，我在指挥中心向您
Agent Lynch, I'm patching surveillance
报告实时监控
from the General's tent to you now.
发现一架V-22斜旋翼飞机
Sir, I have an inbound V- 22 tilt- rotor
从西北方靠近
on approach from the northwest.
是友军，受命于莫里森将军
ldentified friendly. Landing under the General's orders.
这里是总指挥，不要开火，确认友军
Alpha Delta Alpha, stand down. Checked, friendly.
他们是我的人，大家负责掩护
Those are our boys. D- block perimeter around LZ
重要物资着陆
for essential cargo touchdown.
拉塞尔，我们回来了
Russ, we are in the net.
收到，我5分钟后到
Copy that. I will be there in five.
我准备了一瓶好酒给你们接风
l've got a big bottle of Blue Label waiting.
一瓶？我要一箱，葛朗台
A bottle? Make it a case, Scrooge.
一会儿见
- See you in a few.
谁去放他出来？
Who's gonna let him out?
- 你！ - 你！
- You! - You!
等着瞧，我把你们都杀光！
What you don't realize is, now I gotta kill all of y'all!
把你们都杀光！先是汉尼拔，然后默多克！
l'll kill all of y'all! Hannibal first, then Murdock!
- 头儿 - 最后轮到小帅！
- Boss man. I'm gonna save Face for last!
- 我来试试 - 那请便
- Let me try something. Go for it.
奇怪，刚才都不紧张，现在我倒害怕了
ls it weird that I'm more scared now than what we just did?
博斯克，是默多克
Bosco, it's Murdock.
默多克，把门打开！
Murdock, open this door!
一会儿给你吃你最喜欢的椰粉馅饼
l'll make you some of that coconut- curry tapenade that you love.
这招兴许管用
That might work.
加烤肉那种？
With toast points?
当然是加烤肉的，是不是还要就着
Hell, yeah, with toast points. What, you're gonna have that
- 纯香芋片一起吃？ - 那还等什么
- with plain old chips? - Let's do this.
- 妈的！你整我 - 看谁来了
- Damn! You tricked me. - There he is.
- 看谁来了！ - 我被你整惨了！
- There he is! - I hate that!
- 拜托！ - 离我远点，老兄
- Come on! - Get away from me, man!
要不是官阶比你们低，看我不揍扁你们
The only reason I don't kick y'all asses is 'cause you all outrank me.
你们明知道，还骗我被吊上天！
You should know better! You know I hate flying!
- 我现在又脏又臭！ - 呼！耶！
- I'm wet! I stink! Hoo! Yeah!
而且里面的钱一分也不是我的！
And I can't spend none of that money!
- 钱买不来快乐 - 去你的！
- Money can't buy happiness. - Damn, man!
嘿，默多克，你晚上做饭最好把围裙穿上
Hey, Murdock, you cooking tonight. You better get your apron on.
我真是享受计划实现的那一刻
l love it when a plan comes together.
- 汉尼拔，那是谁？ - 将军？
- Hannibal, who was that General?
- 是不是将军？ - 拉塞尔
- ls that the General? - Russ.
- 快去，快去看看！ - 将军！
- Get there. Get in there. General!
- 拉塞尔！ - 将军！
- Russ! - General!
将军！
General!
老天！
Jesus Christ.
派克
Pike.
开火！
Contact rear!
快追！
Get in there!
快追！快追！
Get there, get there!
经过商讨，我们决定将你
After conferring, we've decided to demote you
降职为中尉
to the rank of First Lieutenant.
索莎中尉，我们并不是针对你
Lieutenant Sosa, it's nothing personal,
可你丢了电板
but you lost those plates.
这是玩忽职守
Those were your responsibility.
你应该感到庆幸
Consider yourself lucky.
为此事坐牢的是别人
Others are going to prison over this.
你好，检察官大人
Good day, Director McCready.
中尉，你可以走了
Lieutenant, you're dismissed.
史密斯上校，本庭无法核实
Colonel Smith, this court has been unable to recover
任何证据表明你所申明的是由莫里森将军亲自下令
any direct order from General Morrison for you to conduct the mission
参与此次行动
for which you're being tried.
检察官大人，这是一次秘密行动
Your Honor, this was a covert operation
其间没有任何正式命令
and no official orders were given.
那么唯一可以证明
So the one individual who can verify
此次行动合法性的人已不幸亡故，对吗上校？
the legitimacy of this operation is deceased. ls that correct, Colonel?
不，大人，不是亡故
No, Your Honor, not deceased.
莫里森将军是被谋杀的
General Morrison was murdered.
上校，我戎马一生
Colonel, l've been around a long time.
你们这样的战队我见多了，全是亡命之徒
l've seen units like yours. They're outlaws.
你们这些人是
Units like that pose a direct threat
对我军荣誉和纪律的一大威胁
to the fabric and fundamentals of our military.
各位长官，为什么暮色森林可以逃脱责任？
Your Honors, why hasn't Black Forest been brought to trial?
军事法庭无权审判暮色森林
Black Forest and its personnel are not subject to military jurisdiction.
这次又有什么计划，头儿？说说看？
(WHlSPERlNG) Where's the plan, boss Where is it?
打算怎么逃？我可看不出来了
Where's the escape hatch? Because I don't see it.
- 任务还没结束，中尉 - 什么任务？
- This mission isn't over, Lieutenant. - What mission?
找到派克和电板，洗脱罪名
l clear our names. We find Pike and the plates.
不惜代价
- No matter what.
各位长官，其他人只是服从命令
Your Honors, these men were acting under my command.
任何罪名均应由我一人承担
Any judgment should be levied against me, and me alone.
我反对，长官
Absolutely not, sir.
我们参加此次行动都是出于自愿
We were all participating in this operation willingly.
我不想被单独羁押
l don't wanna be tried separately.
我也拒绝隔离收监，长官
l refuse to be tried separately, sir.
依照《军事审判统一法典》
ln accordance with the Uniform Code of Military Justice,
本庭现对天龙特攻队
this court is rendering guilty verdicts
所有成员做出有罪判决
for each member of this Alpha Unit, or A- Team,
判处在最高安全级别监狱接受隔离关押
and mandating incarceration in separate maximum- security facilities
处有期徒刑10年
for a period of up to 10 years.
现对你们免去所有军衔
You're all hereby stripped of formal rank
并开除军籍
and dishonorably discharged.
滑天下之大稽
- This is bullshit, man.
现在宣布休庭
This session is adjourned.
真是无耻
Disgraceful.
- 别碰我！ - 上尉，退后
- Do not touch me, okay? - Captain, stand down.
肃静！肃静！
Order! Order!
太无耻了！
Absolute disgrace!
满意了吧？你这下满意了？
You happy? Are you happy, Charissa?
上校，管好你的人！
Colonel, control your men!
- 把你的爪子拿开！ - 奇耻大辱！
- Get your hands off me! - This is a disgrace!
6个月后
科罗拉多州卡森基地 军事监狱
你好，林奇先生，好久不见
Well, hello, Mr. Lynch. Long time.
你一点也不紧张嘛，林奇
You look very relaxed, Lynch.
这里可是有监控的
A lot of cameras in here.
没错
(SlGHlNG) Yeah, there are.
只可惜他们现在遇到了点技术上的小麻烦
Yeah, well, they seem to be having some technical issues at the moment.
等回放录像时就会发现了
May not show up till playback.
汉尼拔，我能叫你汉尼拔吗？
Hannibal. Can I call you Hannibal?
反正不能称你为上校了
l can't call you Colonel anymore.
6个月了
Six months.
我一直期待你能逃出去
Been waiting for you to bust out of here
再次聚齐你那几个龙兄虎弟
and round up the rest of the Backstreet Boys
代我找回遗失的电板
and lead me to those plates.
半年连半点消息都没有
Six months and not a peep.
所有人都认定你和你的弟兄是派克一伙的
Everybody thought you and your team were working with Pike.
嗯，除你之外
Mmm. Everybody except you.
派克谋杀了莫里森，偷走电板还栽赃我们特攻队
Pike murdered Morrison. Set me and my boys up and stole those plates.
我知道他的下落
And I know where he is.
没人知道他的下落
Nobody knows where he is.
只有一张图像
lt's a single image of him.
大约一个月前拍到的，在欧洲
Taken about a month ago, somewhere in Europe.
我们猜测是一帧监控录像的截图
We think it's a grab from a CCTV camera.
德国，法兰克福
Frankfurt, Germany.
你是怎么知道的？
(LAUGHS) How did you get that in here?
时间，林奇
Time, Lynch.
给我一分钟我能撂倒一个
Give me a minute and I'm good.
给我一小时我能撂倒十个
lf l've got an hour, I'm great.
给我半年，我就天下无敌了
You give me six months, I'm unbeatable.
我了解派克
l know Pike.
这个阿拉伯人是谁？
Who's the Arab?
我们也不知道
We don't know.
不过猜测他才是整件阴谋的幕后黑手
We think he's the deep, dark, hidden hand in this whole thing.
不是掮客就是买主
Maybe a broker, maybe a buyer.
林奇，我们有共同的敌人 而你也需要我们
Lynch, we have common enemies and you have limited choices.
想要夺回电板，非我们小队莫属
My team is still your best shot at getting those plates back.
那倒未必
l wouldn't be so sure.
那你为什么费尽心机来找我？
Then why did you make the long drive out here?
你和你们总部的那帮废柴只知道纸上谈兵
You and your boys at Langley want your own private printing press.
动动嘴皮子就是爱国主义
That's about as deep as your patriotism goes.
那你想要我做什么？
So, what would you need from me?
我许诺我的队员要还他们以清白
l swore to my team that I would clear our names.
你们应该明白声誉有多重要
You of all people must understand the value of a name.
你听着
Now, listen.
我要官复原职，消除档案
l want full reinstatement and clean records
我和弟兄们都要
for myself and my team.
我没法把你弄出去
l can't get you out of here.
至少不能见阳光
Not legally, at least.
这可是你们中情局的拿手好戏
This is something the boys at Langley do very, very well.
剂量必须精确
Make sure the dosage is right.
要精确到分毫不差
And when I say right, I mean perfect.
Don't seem like happiness will come along
古巴货，真可惜了
(SNlFFS) Cuban. What a shame.
Everybody's throwing rocks in my bed
Just can't seem to get ahead in life
Ooh, nothing I do ever turn out right
Won't somebody help me, please?
'Cause l've been lonely for so long
Don't seem like happiness will come along
l've been lonely...
不许在我的地盘
You are not permitted
撒野！
in my dojo!
没错，你见鬼了老兄…
So, Satan walks into this bar...
等等，这是什么地方？健身泳池吗？
Wait a minute. What's this, a lap pool?
干蒸房？
A dry steam room?
没见过这么蹲大牢的是吧？
Yeah, it'll go a long way with the boys.
你他妈的是怎么搞来的？
How in the hell do you pull this off?
关键不是认识谁，老兄，而是如何认识他们
lt's not who you know, Bob, it's how you know them.
哦！你儿子从阿富汗回来了吗？
Oh! Did your boy get back from Afghanistan?
是的，我和他母亲真应该感谢上帝让他回家
Yeah. Thanks for getting him home. His mother and I are real grateful.
- 上尉 - 嘿
- Captain. - Hey.
你有东西落我床上了
(WHlSPERlNG) You left something on the bed.
- 还以为你藏起来了呢 - 我为什么要这么做？
- Could have hid those. - Why would I want to do that?
8点见
l'll see you at 8:00.
- 现在又要建一个… - 游泳池和干蒸房
And now you want to build... - A lap pool and a dry steam.
这边建个日光浴
Overlooking a sundeck.
嘿，中尉，谢谢你的靴子
Hey, LT, thanks for the boots.
啊，没事，这是我的荣幸，宝贝儿！
Ah! Come on. lt's my pleasure, baby!
漂亮！
Beautiful.
我知道这东西能防止身体被晒伤
Listen, now I know this is good for the body,
可脸怎么防晒呢？
but how do you protect the face?
把脸也抹上呗，小子
You don't mess with it, kid.
了解
Gotcha.
- 谢谢你的款待 - 别客气
- Thanks for the tan. - You got it.
史密斯越狱了，中尉
Smith has escaped, Lieutenant.
派我去抓他吧
Let me go after him.
他们特攻队是派克和暮色森林的同党
Smith and his team were working with Brock Pike and Black Forest.
我能把电板找回来，长官
l can get those plates back for you, sir.
你知道我行的
You know I can.
我是谁？谁是我？
Holla what? Holla who?
我是我！
Holla me.
嘿
Hey.
嘿！放我出去！嘿！嘿！嘿！
Hey! Let me out! Hey, hey! Hey!
当时我看他站在那儿，大吃一惊
l see him standing there, and I was like, "What?"
然后就昏过去了，等我醒来，脸都木了
And then it turned black and I woke up, and my face was numb,
然后…
and I just...
然后你就擦掉他逃出去的脚印
And you mopped up the footprints that led out,
却没发现自己的白大褂
ignored the fact that your lab coat,
通行证、车钥匙和车子同时不见了
pass card, car keys and car were missing.
他好像把史密斯吃了
Looks like he ate Smith.
吉尔伯特，你要不是故意
Gilbert, you've either deliberately
协助一个联邦重犯越狱
aided and abetted a federal fugitive's escape,
就是我所见过的白痴中的极品
or you're the single dumbest human being l've ever come into contact with.
- 你能看出来吗？ - 别说了
- You smell that? - Don't talk about it.
想知道我个人是什么倾向吗？
Would you like to know which way I'm leaning?
向前倾
- Forward.
给这个白痴验尿，马上就做
l would test this man's urine, on the hour.
还有一周我就可以假释了
l was a week away from my parole hearing.
晒成这德性了
You are really tan.
我说过任务还没结束
Told you the mission wasn't over.
我要重召特攻队
I'm putting the team back together.
我需要你，小帅，队里没你不行
l need you, Face. I can't do this without you.
典狱长，没有你的授权也没有签字，是怎么有人
Warden, how did Smith arrange a personal visit without your consent
进来探视的？你作何解释？
or your signature? How does that happen?
你对此到底怎么解释？
How the hell did this guy do that?
封锁这里，任何人不得进入
Seal that up, nobody goes in there.
当天的访客记录不见了
Log- in pages from the day in question have been removed.
- 这有什么大惊小怪的 - 被人撕掉的
- Why does that not surprise me? - Torn out.
雪茄藏在书脊里面
The cigar was in the spine of that book.
- 聪明 - 再看这个
- Subtle. lt's a good book. - Right.
这是全监狱的监控录像对吗？
This is surveillance from all around the prison, right?
嗯
Mmm- hmm.
你现在看到的玩意叫做信号干扰器
What you're watching is a signal jammer.
只要他一走进摄像区
Every time he walks through one of these things,
就有强干扰，他就是这么浑水摸鱼的
we get massive interference. He waltzes in here and waltzes out.
查不出是谁
Nobody knows who he is.
天呐
God.
史密斯上校越狱前抽过的雪茄
Yes. The cigar that Colonel Smith broke out of prison with.
- 没错，想知道有多疯狂吗？ - 说
Yeah. Wanna hear the crazy part? - Yes.
实验室检测出致命剂量的河豚毒素
Lab reports show lethal amounts of, wait for it, tetrodotoxin.
河豚毒素？什么东西？
Tetrodotoxin? What is that?
- 足以致命的毒素 - 没错，睡美人的伎俩
- The near- death drug. - Yes, that sleeping beauty thing.
知道谁最喜欢用这个吗？
Yeah. And you know who likes to use that, right?
- 谁？ - 中情局的朋友
- Who? - Our friends at Langley.
这是他们的最爱
lt's one of their favorites.
得了，你真以为是中情局派人探视的？
Come on, do you really think that the ClA came to the prison to visit Smith?
听起来挺疯狂，但我相信就是他们干的好事
This sounds kind of crazy, but I think the ClA broke him out.
谁救的我们？
Who put us on?
我们在巴格达见过，中情局的林奇
The same guy that put us on in Baghdad. Lynch, ClA.
我们的要求呢？清除档案和复职？
What are we talking about? Clean records? Reinstatements?
通通满足
All of the above.
那派克和电板怎么办？
What about Pike and the plates?
血债血偿
Payback.
他们手里拿的什么东西给对方？
What are they exchanging What is that?
是所谓的干扰器吗？
ls that how he got this in here?
看这两张图片有什么不同
One of these things is not like the other.
我讨厌看图找错
l suck at these games.
这个车牌是哪儿的？看这个车牌
Where's this plate from? What is that plate?
F开头，德国法兰克福
lt's an "F." Frankfurt, Germany.
哦，德国法兰克福
Oh, Frankfurt, Germany.
史密斯在指引我们，这绝不是偶然
Smith is talking to us. This is not accidental.
这个家伙想来不打无准备之仗
With this guy, there's a plan and two to back it up.
我还以为你在号子里一心向善了呢
l take it you didn't get religion inside.
不，仇必须报
No. I got revenge.
很好
Good.
我认识几个人也有同样的想法
l know a couple of guys that'll feel the exact same way.
那就指望他们了
I'm counting on it.
加州塔霍湖畔
绍贝尔监狱转送车
《宽容与怜悯》
“走紧急出口”
Emergency exit now.
汉尼拔
Hannibal.
巴库斯，别乱来！
Baracus, don't do it!
他要去哪儿？他去哪儿？
Where he going What's he doing, man?
巴库斯！该死！
Baracus! God damn it!
索莎
Sosa.
中尉，贝克已经越狱了
Lieutenant, Peck's already gone.
什么？
What?
就剩下巴库斯和默多克，看着办吧，中尉
Baracus and Murdock are left. Handle it, Lieutenant.
好吧，好的
Right. Okay.
我可不想再像上次那么丢人现眼了，你呢？
l don't want to be embarrassed like this again. Do you?
好的，不不不不，我们已经展开部署了
Okay. No, no, no, no. We're gonna catch and deploy from here.
贝克逃了
Peck escaped.
- 见鬼，你认为是史密斯干的？ - 还用说
- Oh, hell. You think Smith is involved? - Definitely.
找出他们的画像，任何能帮助辨认他们的东西
Get graphics on him and Smith. Anything that'll lD them instantly.
我知道他们把默多克关在曼海姆一家疯人院里
l know they got Murdock in a psych ward in Mannheim.
好，好，该死的巴库斯在哪儿？
Right. Okay. Where the hell is B.A. Baracus?
你怎么就确信那扇车门
How did you know that once that door was extracted
- 能承受他的大块头？ - 凭直觉，他有…
- that it would take his weight? - I just did. He's...
- 他大概有225到230磅吧？ - 230磅
- You know, he's what, 225, 230 pounds? - 230. Yeah.
还记得7年前在委内瑞拉抓的那个混蛋吗？
Remember the gag we did in Venezuela seven years ago?
委内瑞拉，记得，记得
Venezuela. Yeah. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
可他是个土行孙
But that was a midget.
算了 ，不跟你争
Yeah, I wouldn't go for that.
- 嘿，大块头过来了 - 是啊，他归队了
- Hey, big guy. There he is. - Yeah! He's back.
- 很高兴回来 - 来吧
- Yeah, it's good to be back. Come on.
- 很高兴回来 - 老伙计
- lt's good to be back. My man.
- 很高兴见到你老弟 - 我也是，我也是
- lt's good to see you, bud. - You, too, bro. You, too.
- 谢谢 - 你气色不错
- Thanks. - You look well.
见到你们真开心
lt's good to see you guys.
- 怎么了？ - 你的莫西干发型呢？
- What? - Where's the Mohawk?
怎么，不喜欢我的新头型吗老弟？
What, you don't like my new do, man?
喜欢？不是给你理发剪了吗，我还以为…
Do I like it? Well, we got you the clippers. I thought...
我用过了
Yeah, I used them.
嘿，出什么事了大块头？
Hey. What's up, big guy?
说啊，大家自己人
Come on, you can speak to us.
伙计们
Guys...
我不能再杀人了
l can't kill anybody.
- 什么意思？ - 我发过誓
- What do you mean? - l've taken a vow.
- 发誓？ - 不参与暴力
- Vow? - Of non- violence.
我仍然会为你们做任何事，相信我
l'll still do anything for you guys, you know that.
就是不能杀人
But I just can't kill, man.
虽然本性难移
Old habits may die hard,
但始终可以改掉
but they still gotta die.
我小时候听的最多的就是
When I was a kid, all you heard in the hood was,
“博斯克是个坏蛋，无恶不作”
"Bosco's a badass, out collecting scalps."
那时我就留起了莫西干的发型
That's where the Mohawk came from.
整天打打杀杀
Was always at war.
这就是战士的意义所在啊
And that's what warriors are for.
汉尼拔，我不怀念那种生活
Hannibal, man. I don't miss that life.
不管怎样，我会帮你救出默多克
l'll help you get Murdock, and right that wrong,
- 但绝不杀人 - 派克呢？
- but I can't kill. Even Pike?
即便杀了他能为自己洗脱罪名？
Even if killing him would clear your name?
我需要洗净的是自己的良心
My conscience is the only thing I need clear.
说吧，默多克那个疯子在哪？
Now, where's that crazy- ass fool?
移情
Transference.
情感治疗
Healing feelings.
这些东西藏是藏不住的，懂吗？
You can't warehouse these things, you know?
你要表达，要倾诉
You have to express to progress.
一定要点亮感情的灯塔
We gotta empower your emotional tower
照射出自爱与宽容的光芒
and send out a wavelength of self- love and acceptance.
谢谢
Thank you.
德国曼海姆 军事精神病院
预备
Clear.
这招对他好像完全不管用 我还从未见过这样的病例
He seems completely impervious to it. lt's impossible to develop a base reading.
试过增加电压了吗？
Have you increased the voltage?
每次都在增加
Every single session, yes.
- 情感治疗，宝贝 - 还有呢？
- Healing feelings, baby. - And?
就这么点能耐吗？来吧
ls that all you got? Here we go.
预备
Clear.
咦哈！
Yee- ha!
耶，这才有点意思了
Yeah, I think I might have felt something there.
哦不，我不睡觉
Oh, no, I won't sleep.
霍华德·利特尔
Howard Little.
有个阿尼拔·史密斯寄给你的包裹
You have a package here from an Annabelle Smith.
我不认识什么阿尼拔·史密斯
l don't know any Annabelle Smith.
你当然认识，老霍
Sure you do, Howie.
当然认识，阿尼拔嘛
Sure you do, baby. Annabelle.
还记得越南岘港那个护士吗？ 红头发，双腿截肢那个？
Remember the nurse from Da Nang? The redhead, double amputee?
职业滑翔者？对！
Professional hang glider? Yes!
伙计们
Guys.
阿尼拔
Annabelle.
没错，没错
Yeah. Yeah.
阿尼拔
Annabelle.
阿尼拔你真是太有才了，看看啊
Annabelle. You have outdone yourself. Look at this.
- 太真实了 - 美女
- lt's so real. - Beauty.
还有部3D电影
A movie in three dimensions.
立正，士兵
Stand- to, soldier.
- 德军在西线集结 - 我的老天
- Jerries advancing on the western front. - Good heavens.
交给你一项绝密任务
Got a secret mission for you.
把这些眼镜分发给所有人
Take these and distribute them amongst the men.
- 遵命，长官 - 别让女王失望
- Yes, sir. - Don't fail the Queen.
- 是，长官 - 很好
- No, sir. - Great.
是，长官
Yes, sir.
电影，电影，电影…
(CHANTlNG) Movie, movie, movie...
封你为骑士
l knight you.
阁下，你需要把头低下，站起来重来
Sir, you have to put your head down. Stand up and do it again.
电影，电影…
Movie, movie...
现在为女王祝唱，我喊预备…还没开始呢
Now let's sing to the Queen. When I ask you... Not yet.
- 电影，电影！ - 电影，电影！
- Movie, movie... - Movie, movie...
你有眼镜！你有眼镜！
You get glasses! You get glasses!
好球！
Ball!
下跪的时候，直接把头也低下
When you kneel, you put your head down straightaway.
对视是不礼貌的，懂吗？
Looking me in the eye is disrespectful. Do you understand?
电影，电影…
Movie, movie...
你又在盯着我看，这是不对的
You're looking me in the eye now. That's wrong.
电影，电影，电影…
Movie, movie, movie...
“潜水侠”，喂！
Aquaman? Hello.
你有眼镜！你有眼镜！
You get glasses! You get glasses!
起立，3D爵士，欣赏电影吧
Rise, Sir 3D, and enjoy your motion picture.
- 电影，电影！ - 电影，电影！
- Movie! Movie! - Movie! Movie!
哥们，这有点太疯狂了吧
Boy, could I use two hours of not this.
把镇静剂发下去，再给这帮疯子要几份披萨
Pass out the sedatives and order some pizzas for these freaks.
- 电影，电影！ - 电影，电影！
- Movie, movie... - Movie, movie...
电影…
Movie...
该死
Shit.
抱歉，有什么事吗？
Excuse me, can I help you with something?
有，默多克上尉在哪？
Yes. Captain Murdock, where is he?
- 这边请 - 谢谢
Right through there. - Thank you.
魔鬼
El diablo.
好了，嘘，安静
Okay.  Settle down.
观影期间禁止喧哗
No talking during the movie.
倒栽葱！
Down in front!
快看，3D耶！
Look, it's 3D, man!
我讨厌3D！
I'm sick of 3D.
默多克上尉
Captain Murdock.
我们在巴格达见过还记得吗？
You remember me from Baghdad?
算了，别耽误工夫了，这家伙已经疯了
Okay, this is pointless. This guy is fried.
没错，否则他也不会呆在这
Yeah, there's a reason why he's in here.
他的队友都逃出去了，唯独他没有
And his entire team has escaped, except him.
电影！
Movie!
四处看看，确保没有其他人来
Take a look around anyway. Let's make sure he's alone.
遵命，长官
Yes, ma'am.
上尉，恭候大驾
Oh, Captain, your chariot awaits.
抱歉了哥几个，得走了！电影你们自己看
Sorry, boys, gotta run! Can't finish the movie.
别忘了告诉我结尾
Do let me know how it ends.
克里萨，你藏哪儿去了？再见了宝贝
Charissa, where are you hiding? Stay beautiful, baby.
- 开车，大头 - 走了，白痴
- Punch it, B.A. - Let's go, fool.
去开车！
Get the truck!
她居然冲我们开枪
She's actually shooting at us.
你们真该戴上3D眼睛看看子弹
You guys should see these bullets in 3D!
- 默多克，快坐好！ - 就像真的打在身上一样！
- Murdock, get in here! - lt's like we're actually being shot at!
他们本来就想打在你身上，白痴！
You are getting shot at, you crazy- ass fool!
- 快停车！ - 冲过去！
- Stop right there! - Ram it.
嘿，给我停车！
Hey! I said halt!
爽！抱歉了兄弟！
Damn! Sorry, dude.
他们好像驶向停机坪方向
lt looks like they're headed for the tarmac.
快追，快追
Let's go, let's go, let's go.
- 诸位 - 老天爷，是汉尼拔·史密斯
- Gentlemen. - Holy shit, that's Hannibal Smith.
你们有谁全副武装又被联邦通缉？
Are any of you armed and/or wanted federal fugitives?
- 没有 - 我们都是
- No. - Well, we're both.
- 所以请吧 - 真是个馊主意
- Which means... This is a bad idea.
馊主意
This is a bad idea.
别娘娘腔了，你是个大男人，快上飞机
Stop being a baby. You're a grown- ass man. Get on the plane.
- 你要劫持飞机吗？ - 要不我参军干吗！
- You're taking the plane? - And that's why I joined the Army.
这是大逃亡的最后一步，快上去
We gotta finish the escape. Man up and get in there.
军中明星，谢谢了各位，恕不远送
The best and brightest. Appreciate it, boys. That'll be all.
钥匙在哪？把钥匙给我
Who's got the keys? I just need your keys.
什么钥不钥匙的！我不坐飞机，不需要钥匙
What you talking about keys? You don't need no keys for no plane.
- 必须得有钥匙 - 干什么？真是糟透了
- I do need keys. - For what? This is a bad idea.
我们刚把他从疯人院捞出来
We just broke this guy out of a psych ward.
汉尼拔，你却把真正的飞行员赶跑了
Hannibal, you let the real pilots go.
- 大头，放松，不会有事的 - 吃一颗这个
- B.A., relax. You're gonna be fine. - Take one of these.
这是什么？安眠药吗？它最好是
What is this? Will it knock me out? lt better knock me out,
要是我睡不着，我就让你躺下
'cause if it don't, I'm gonna knock you out.
博斯克，这么多按钮把我搞糊涂了
Bosco, the buttons are confusing me.
- 闭嘴，默多克 - 赶紧，默多克，起飞
- Shut up, Murdock. Come on, Murdock. Let's go.
你来驾驶飞机？算了，我还是自首去吧
You gonna fly this plane? Forget it. l'll turn myself in.
- 这个是干嘛的？ - 快啊
What does this do? - Come on.
- 赶紧，默多克 - 走运了
- Come on, Murdock. - I got lucky.
抓紧了各位
Hang on, boys.
停！停！停！
Stop. Stop, stop, stop.
小帅，你马子来了
Face, your girlfriend is back.
- 快倒车！ - 这帮孙子！
- Reverse now. Son of a bitch!
快他妈的倒车！
Move your ass now.
- “大力神”飞机对阵奔驰汽车 - 起飞，默多克
- The C- 1 30 versus the Mercedes- Benz. - Lift us off, Murdock.
- 要不要开快点？ - 加速！
- How about faster? - Faster!
我在试，但车子卡住了
I'm trying. I got it pinned!
老天爷！
Oh, my God!
给我接塔台
Get us to flight control.
女士们先生们，飞机正在经历气流
Ladies and gentlemen, we are expecting slight turbulence.
请在坐好并系好安全带，待指示灯熄灭后
Please remain in your seats until the captain has turned off
方可打开
the "Fasten Seatbelt" sign.
别担心，伙计们，气流从未引起过坠机！
Don't worry, boys! Turbulence has never brought down a plane!
这他妈的是怎么回事？
- What the hell is that?
但要是有亚音速导弹无人机的话
But we got inbound subsonic UAVs with missile lock!
十有八九会坠机！
And they bring down planes all the time!
好，它们来了，发射反导诱饵！
Okay, they're coming in. Launching countermeasures!
哇！
Whoa!
看见了吗？我玩的调虎离山！
Did you see that? That's my diversion!
猛虎敌不过好猎手！
They die on this version.
坐稳！坐稳！我要做翻滚了！
Hang on! Hang on! Hold on! We're going over.
默多克，你小子要干什么？
Murdock, what the hell are you doing?
大伙还记得墨西哥吗？
(WHOOPS) You boys remember Mexico?
哇！
Whoa!
女士们先生们，各位请注意
Ladies and gentlemen, from the flight deck,
现在透过舷窗向右手方向望去
if you look out of the right- hand side of the aircraft, you'll notice
您会发现右翼已经起火
that your right wing is on fire.
目标锁定，请求发射，长官
Tango reacquired. Missile lock pending, sir.
我是国防部的克里萨·索莎中尉 少校，不要击落那架飞机
Lieutenant Charissa Sosa, DClS. Major, do not shoot that aircraft down.
出动战斗机逼他们迫降
Scramble fighters and force them to land.
飞机上有联邦重犯
There are federal fugitives on that plane.
他们还劫持了美国陆军的飞机
They've also stolen property from the U.S. Army.
比利，比利，给我转无人机实时监控录像
Billy, Billy, I need you to get the nose- cam view up here on my monitor now.
接通了，长官
lt's up, sir. Here it is.
导弹发射，长官！
Missile away, sir.
成功击落，“大力神”运输机被拦截并摧毁
We have shoot- down. Hercules has been intercepted and destroyed.
抱歉，中尉，实在抱歉
Sorry, Lieutenant. I'm sorry.
- 搞什么花样 - 坦克上有降落伞
- I don't believe it. - We have chute deployment on the Buford.
什么？
What?
把无人机撤回，马上！
l want these drones taken offline right now!
- 它们在3000英里以外 - 不管谁在遥控这些飞机
- They're 3,000 miles away. - Whoever is running those drones.
不管谁在负责，我要跟他直接通话
Get me a direct line to whoever is running those drones.
快把无人机撤离，要不我真要吃不了兜着走了
We gotta get these drones to stand down or I'm gonna be on bitch duty.
我要捉活的！
l need to get those men alive!
大家还好吗？
Everybody okay?
你觉得他们会认为我们已经死了吗？
What are the chances they think we're dead?
不怎么觉得
Not great.
- 跟我说我们没在飞机上 - 我们没在飞机上
- Tell me we ain't still on that plane. - We ain't on that plane.
- 汉尼拔！ - 说
Hannibal! - Yeah?
要是不高于2万英尺，我们还能呼吸，对吧？
lf we're under 20,000 feet, we can still breathe, right?
你说什么？2万英尺？
What are you talking about, 20,000 feet?
- 看来要开上几炮了 - 搞什么啊？
- Let's fire up the old weapons system. - What the hell, man?
嘿，博斯克，太闷了，我开个窗！
Hey, Bosco, a little stuffy. I'm gonna pop a window!
耶！
Yeah!
放马过来吧，孙子，放马过来！
What you got, bitches? What you got?
耶！
Yeah!
让我也过过瘾，小帅！来啊！
Let me have a turn, Face! Come on!
- 我们怎么会在一辆下坠的坦克里？ - 因为飞机坠毁了！
- Why are we in a falling tank? - Because the plane exploded!
什么？什么时候？
What... What? When?
刚刚！
Recently!
- 被掠食者击中了！ - 什么掠食者？
- The Reapers shot it down! - What Reapers?
外面还在把我们赶尽杀绝的那几架！
The same ones that are still trying to kill us!
- 我恨你，汉尼拔！ - 技术上讲，我们不是在飞行
- I blame you, Hannibal! - Technically, we're not flying.
我知道！因为我们在坠落，白痴！
l know! Because we're falling, fool!
老天！
Oh, Jesus!
2号无人机坠机，我们损失了一架
UAV- 2 has splashed down. We just lost one of the drones.
汉尼拔，有麻烦了！
Hannibal, we're in trouble!
都抓紧了！
Brace yourselves!
帅呆了！
Awesome!
小帅，开启主炮塔！
Face, get on to the main gun!
下面半英里外有个湖
There's a lake a half- mile away from this position.
- 你让我开炮打什么？ - 相信我！
- What the hell am I trying to hit? - Trust me!
- 炮塔旋转82度 - 开火！
- Rotate the turret 82 degrees. - Fire in the hole!
- 开火！ - 轰！
- Fire! - Boom!
开火！
Fire!
他们要击落另一架无人机吗？
Are they trying to shoot down that other drone?
不，他们在“飞”那辆坦克
No. They're trying to fly that tank.
- 他在飞坦克！ - 坦克是飞不了的，白痴！
- He's flying the tank! - You can't fly a tank, fool!
- 旋转16度！ - 收到！
- Rotate 1 6 degrees! - Got it!
开火！
Fire!
再旋转34度！
Rotate 34 degrees now!
- 汉尼拔… - 等等…
- Hannibal... - Wait...
开火！
- Fire!
- 塔台，无人机失去联系… - 谁批准开火的？
Control, we have lost... - ls that a confirmed hit?
炮塔正对地面待命！
Bring turret full- front and wait!
默多克，关闭舱门！
Murdock! Close the hatch!
舱门，好的！管用吗？
Hatch, okay! Did that work? Did that work?
- 头儿！ - 来吧宝贝！
- Boss! - Come on, baby.
- 来吧 - 舱门控制？
- Come on. - Hatch control?
我还没活够！
I'm too young to die!
头儿，下面什么都没有！
Boss! I'm aiming at nothing!
快啊
Come on.
- 不胜荣幸，诸位 - 快啊宝贝
lt's been an honor, gentlemen. - Come on, baby.
最拉风的飞行永远是最后一次，上校！
The greatest ride is the last ride, Colonel!
- 随意开火！ - 来啊宝贝！
- Fire everything! - Come on, baby!
- 你们都去见鬼吧！完蛋了！ - 快啊！
Get right with God, y'all! This is it! - Come on!
哈！
Yee- ha!
这对鱼儿不公平！
lt's not fair to the fish!
这是作弊！
You're cheating!
你总是唠唠叨叨
You with your nagging...
把鱼都吓跑了！
...you're chasing them away!
德国法兰克福 美国中情局办事处
好了，辛勤的小蜜蜂
All right. Busy bees, busy bees.
伙计们，把外套脱了吧，这里热死了
Guys, you can take your coats off. Hot as hell in here.
我都快热成白痴了
I'm sweating like a whore in church.
- 长官 - 什么？
- Sir. - Yeah?
史密斯他们在德国曼海姆劫持一架军用运输机
Smith and his team were engaged in a C- 1 30 over Mannheim, Germany,
被两架掠食者追踪
by two Reaper drones.
不知道是不是加密电文
I'm not sure if it's an encryption glitch,
但上面说他们在坦克中被击落
but it says that they were shot down in a tank.
防空司令部想说成是失踪，但报告没法写
NORAD's calling it an X- out, but there is a conflicting report.
这还用你说
I'm sure there is.
有个德国老太太说看见一辆坦克
l've got a German Hausfrau who says she saw a tank
从湖水里开出来，上面的人很像默多克…
drive up and out of Lake Wolgastsee with a guy resembling Murdock...
劳驾，柏林怎么走？
Excuse me, which way to Berlin?
- …还冲老太太问路 - 这不可能
- ...asking for directions to Berlin. -  That's impossible.
这星期史密斯都死两次了
Well, this will be the second time Smith has died this week.
这个可能吗？
ls that possible?
有什么发现？
- What have you got for me? - Look at this.
斯图加特 美军欧洲司令部
这是修正的史密斯接受探视的录像
We just got the unscrambled composite of Smith's visitor in prison,
但目前还没有辨明身份
but with no lD on the subject yet.
你好，帅哥
Hello, handsome.
等等，这个人我见过
Wait, l've seen this person before.
我认识他
l know this guy.
巴格达
Baghdad.
给我接通中情局总部 有事做了
Get me a clean patch to Langley. We're going fishing.
从以前从未听说过这件事
l barely even heard about it.
有也只是只言片语，但怎么能确定是我们呢？
l mean, I heard bits and pieces of it, but how much of that was us?
- 有一个电话… - 我在说话
- So, I have a... - I was talking.
- 不是我们 - 你先停下好吗？
- lt's never us. - Can you stop?
国防部的索莎中尉来电
l have a DoD hardline from Lieutenant Sosa.
她找林奇探员
She's looking for Agent Lynch.
就说他不在
He's not available, ever.
林奇探员，记得巴格达吗？
Agent Lynch, from Baghdad?
莫里森将军的帐篷？
General Morrison's tent?
出去
Out.
为什么雇她这样的？
Why do we have her?
她人品好，就因为这个
She's got a fantastic personality. That's why.
请问哪位？
With whom am I speaking?
索莎中尉，是林奇探员吗？
This is Lieutenant Sosa. ls this Agent Lynch?
抱歉，只知道你姓什么
I'm sorry, I don't have a first name.
我也是，有何贵干，中尉？
Neither do l. So, what can I do you for, Lieutenant?
我这儿有幅你的照片
I'm looking at an image of you
在戒备森严的卡森监狱拍的
from the disciplinary barracks at Fort Carson.
很销魂！
(WHlSPERlNG) She's hot.
汉尼拔史密斯上校在押期间你是不是探过监？
Did you visit former Colonel Hannibal Smith in prison?
我不明白你在说什么，前上尉
l don't know what you're talking about, former Captain.
林奇探员，如果真是你协助史密斯越狱
Agent Lynch, if you facilitated Smith's escape
而且目前还在资助、教唆他们的话…
and are currently aiding and abetting him...
哦，老兄
Ooh. Buddy.
要是你能办到这种事
lf you can make something like that stick,
你就可以直接晋升上将了
your next promotion should be in the five- star range.
要是你在帮他们夺取电板的话
And if you're helping to retrieve those engraving plates,
休怪我翻脸不认人
I'm going to have to go out of my way to disappoint you.
我要她的电话、电脑、任何她用到的设备和工具
l want her phones, her computers, any support packages she operates.
我要查查她，监听她所有的通讯记录
l wanna know everything. I want active intercept taps on everything she's got.
从现在起监视她的一举一动
l want every move monitored from this moment forward.
他可是国防部的人
You realize she's DoD.
天王老子也不怕，给我查！
l don't care if she's G- O- D. Do it.
头儿，看这个
Boss, check this out.
从派克这张照片我们查到了法拉克福的康尼克银行
We've tracked this photograph of Pike to the K?nigsbank in Frankfurt.
监控录像显示他和一个神秘阿拉伯男子
Our surveillance has him and an unknown Arab
在过去的一个月一直在
making regular trips from the train station to the bank
车站和银行间穿梭
all over the last month.
- 派克太大意了 - 既然被我们盯上
- Pike's getting sloppy. - Yeah, but if we're onto him,
他同时被史密斯他们盯上的几率有多大？
what are the odds that Smith and his team are onto Pike and the Arab, too?
不可能，我们直接从国防部拿到的情报
No, no, no, this is a direct pull- down from the Pentagon's database.
史密斯他们不可能接触到这些的
There's absolutely no way Smith and his team could have this stuff.
我觉得应该假设史密斯掌握的情报一直都比我们多
l think we should assume they have more information than us at all times.
上个月派克陆续把电板
Pike has been moving the stolen engraving plates
转移到法兰克福的康尼克银行大厦
to the K?nigsbank Tower in Frankfurt over the past month.
明天，最后一批电板
Tomorrow, the last of the cases containing these plates
会交到那个阿拉伯人手里
will be transferred to the Arab.
也就是说六个月以来这些电板
This will mark the only time in the last six months
是第一次集中出现
that all of the plates have been in one location.
这是我们最好也是最后的机会
lt's our best and only shot at getting them back.
他们从康尼克大厦出发坐7:15去苏黎世的火车
They leave the K?nigsbank Tower for the 7:15 train to Zürich.
各位，我们的任务就是阻止他们上车
Gentlemen, we're gonna make sure they miss that train.
- 小帅？ - 在
- Face? - Yeah.
该去找人叙叙旧了
Time to bring in your former flame.
要是我没看走眼的话
lf she's as good as I think,
她应该已经在去法兰克福的路上了，去找电板
then she'll be on her way to Frankfurt to intercept those plates.
- 为什么把她也算上？ - 她很有干劲
- Why would you tip her off? - She's a crusader,
到时候有用得着的地方
and we're gonna need her teed up at some point.
都放机灵了伙计们
Keep your eyes and ears open, boys.
克里萨·索莎…
Charissa Sosa...
与此同时
Now the wrinkle.
如果索莎盯上我们，林奇也很可能盯上索莎
lf Sosa's onto us, we can assume that Lynch is onto her.
如果他认定索莎会夺取电板
And if he thinks she stands beteen him and those plates,
就会对她痛下杀手
he won't hesitate to kill her.
小帅，你去车站
Face, get to the train station.
我是索莎
This is Sosa.
要是林奇真找麻烦，你去解决
lf there's a threat from Lynch, deal with it.
喂？
- Hello?
可以开枪，重复，可以开枪
Shoot is green. Say again, shoot is green.
喂？
Hello?
出岔子了
Something's wrong.
我们被盯上了，伙计们，快撤，离开这鬼地方
We're marked, guys. Pull back. I don't like this at all.
盯人，别被盯上
See. Don't be seen.
- 你好，美女 - 你可真够胆啊
Hello, beautiful. - You have got some balls.
- 是你把手机丢给我的？ - 形势所迫，亲爱的
- You put a drop phone on me? - I had to, babe.
只有这样才能跟你搭上话 林奇监听了你所有的通讯
lt's the only way I could talk to you. Lynch has all your comm lines.
- 赶紧把你的人都撤走 - 我会找到你的，小帅
- I want you to pull your team now. - I'm gonna find you, Face.
不要被她或者任何人发现
But do not engage her or anyone else directly.
还是我找你吧
Not if I find you first.
来啊…好了，好了
Come on, all right... Okay. Okay.
哦！哦！老天！
Ow! Ow! Jesus!
- 你到底在干什么？ - 我在救你！
- What the hell are you doing? - Trying to save you!
克里萨
Charissa.
你知道我们是无辜的，你很清楚
Come on, you know we're innocent. You know this.
你撒谎，当初在巴格达就不该信你
You're lying. Like you lied in Baghdad.
我不知道，不知道那些电板的事
l did not know. I knew nothing about the plates.
当时…当时不知道
At that... At that time.
你这个伪君子！
You are completely full of shit!
别再装模作样了
Will you stop selling yourself on that
当初是你先欺骗了我！
and avoiding the fact that you lied to me!
- 是你先误导我的 - 什么时候？
- You're the one that misled me. - When?
- 又来了，真要我翻旧账吗？ - 翻就翻！
- Come on. You wanna go there? - Yeah, let's go there.
你知道我只是想玩玩，你也想玩玩
You heard I was a player and you wanted to play.
我真情投入你又怕了！
And then I got serious and you freaked!
- 我怕了？我没有！ - 有，你有！
- Oh, I freaked? I did not freak! - Yes, you did.
你害怕了所以一走了之
You panicked and you ran.
克里萨，拜托
Charissa, come on.
我现在是个逃犯，你知道事情的严重性
I'm a federal fugitive. You know exactly how wanted I am.
你以为我大老远跑来就是和你提伤心事来了？不是！
You think I came to Frankfurt to hash out some old heartbreak? No!
我敢来是因为我们是清白的 我敢来是因为有人陷害我们
I'm here because we didn't do this. I'm here because we were set up.
我敢来是因为真相值得我们去冒险
I'm here because, in the end, the truth is worth the risk.
即便你不相信我，我还是相信你
And I believe in you, even if you don't believe in me.
天呐，我都忘了你有多漂亮了
God, I forgot how beautiful you are.
手机拿好
Hold on to that phone.
老天爷！
OH MY GOD!
那人有枪！
HE'S GOT A GUN!
他在那！他有枪！
RlGHT THERE! HE'S GOT A GUN!
枪啊！
A GUN!
孙子
Sucker.
- 糟糕 - 贝克在哪儿？
- Oh, shit. - Where's Peck?
问的好，去找啊！
Excellent question. Find him!
请保持冷静，寻找最近的出口
Please stay calm and go to the nearest exit.
德国法兰克福 康尼克银行大厦
3号通道情况如何
Meet you up on corridor three.
3号通道情况正常
Three to base. We're all clear at this time.
包裹安全之后立即报告
Give me confirmation as soon as the package is secure.
注意密切监控
We need a video feed.
好了，出发吧
Okay, let's dance.
我们下楼了，各单位准备行动
Coming down. Positions, prepare to move.
跟往常一样，跟紧我，先生
As always, stay close to me, sir.
10楼遇袭
Closing off the 10th floor.
10楼，请求支援
Tenth floor, we need backup.
退后！退后！
Get back! Get back!
什么也看不见
l can't see anything.
情况怎么样，头儿？
How we doing there, big man?
默多克，抓到阿拉伯人了
Murdock, here comes the Arab.
一记漂亮的长传
And here's a long drive
球传到左中场
hit deep into left center field.
默多克回撤遇阻，他接住了！
Murdock's back, he's at the wall, and he makes the catch!
我喘不上气了
l can't breathe.
我们被袭击了！
lt's a trap!
彼得，请求支援！
Pete, we need backup!
大头，箱子掉了
B.A., I lost the case.
我现在杀出去
I'm taking fire. I'm out of here.
大头，去找箱子
B.A., get to those plates.
德联邦政府人员已对康尼克银行大厦
Deutsche Federal is responding to explosions and shots fired
- 交火事件做出反应 - 我们现在就出发
- at the K?nigsbank building. - Get us out of this mess and get us
- 马上去那幢大厦 - 遵命，长官
- to that building as soon as possible. - Yes, ma'am.
是你逼我这么做的，巴库斯
You made me work for this one, Baracus.
没想到我会这么狼狈
l didn't think I was this out of shape.
不过我认了
l am, unfortunately.
你的同伙呢？
Where's the rest of the team, huh?
史密斯，贝克，还有个白痴飞行员，叫什么来着？
Smith. Peck. That idiot pilot, the asshole. What's his name?
我要好好教训教训你，巴库斯，看你有什么本事
I'm gonna take this one out of your ass, Baracus. Let's see what you got.
来啊，怎么了？累了吗？
Come on. What are you doing? What, are you tired?
我不想伤害你，老弟
I'm not gonna hurt you, man.
就怕你没那个能耐，尝尝我的厉害吧
No, you're not gonna hurt me, I'm gonna hurt you.
- 我不想杀你 - 不想杀我？
- I don't wanna kill you, man. - You don't wanna kill me?
你不想杀我，那我就杀了你，巴库斯
You're not gonna kill me. I'm gonna kill you, Baracus.
我不是说着玩的，派克
I'm not playing with you, Pike.
听着，我有两支枪，我是左撇子，还记得吗？
Here we go, because I got two guns. I'm a lefty, remember that, right?
所以还没等你扣扳机我就已经开火了
So, as soon as that hammer goes back, it's on.
我发誓我会开枪的
l swear to God, l'll do it.
你不是个懦夫，对吧？
You're not a coward, are you?
对吗？
- Are you?
哦
Whoopsy.
该死！
Damn!
- 要搭车吗，大块头？ - 真是及时雨啊，头儿
- Need a ride, big fella? - You're a life- saver, man.
我可不想开枪杀人
l couldn't shoot him.
让开！趴下！趴下！
Get out of the way! Get down! Get down!
美国军方！放下武器！
U.S. Military! Put them down. Put them down.
美国军方，我们抓住他了
- This is U.S. Military. We got him.
抓我就得来这么大场面
Yeah, this is about the right amount of cops.
油腔滑调，有这么多人围观，算你走运
That's cute. You're lucky there are people around.
美人儿，走运的是你
No, sweetheart, you're lucky.
真要生吃吗？
You eat that cold?
有的吃就不错了
Any way I can get it.
房顶还漏水
There's a leak in the roof.
漏的还不少
There's a lot of them.
- 他们回来了？ - 我去看看
ls that them? - I got it.
阿拉伯人什么也不肯说
All right. Not a peep out of the Arab.
索莎去了火车站
Sosa was at the train station.
- 你见到她了？ - 是
- You saw her? - Yeah.
说话了？
Did you talk to her?
我没得选，好不好？你应该相信我
l had no choice, okay? Just trust me on that.
我相信你会把事情搞砸
l trust you to make historically bad decisions
只要有女人在
- as far as women are concerned.
你是不是只会用下半身思考？
What part of you is thinking at the moment?
林奇的人要袭击她，我只能出手
Lynch's men moved in on her and I had to react.
这也是你派我去的目的嘛
That's why you wanted me there in the first place...
派你去干活！而不是泡妞！
To stop them! Not to engage her!
我不见她怎么干活啊
l couldn't do one without the other.
拜托，谁知道呢
Please. Somehow I doubt that.
嘿，干吗这么恼火？不是拿到电板了吗
Hey. What are you so pissed about? We got the plates.
你说用得着她，现在用得着了
You wanted her teed up. She's teed up.
她知道我们是清白的
She knows we didn't steal them.
她也想找出真正的凶手
She'll be thrilled to find out who did.
什么？
What?
你早该知道
You had to know.
你早该知道要是留我一条命 就迟早会有这一天的
You had to know if you left me alive, that this was coming.
你怎么会不知道呢？
How could you not?
我的本领都是你教的
You taught me almost everything I know.
汉尼拔，你认识他？
Hannibal. You know who this is?
我们都认识
We all do.
莫里森？
Morrison?
不是吧
Hell, no.
老天爷
Jesus Christ.
不知道这算不算是祝愿——祝你们好运，朋友
Not so sure that it is a blessing, but good hunting, my friend.
谢谢
Thank you.
你这个孙子
You son of a bitch.
莫里森？真该死！
Morrison? Holy shit.
你也配做将军！？
You're not a general.
怎么能干出这种勾当？
How could you do this to him?
怎么能这么对我们？
How could you do this to us?
你根本就不在乎自己的弟兄
You know nothing about leading men.
我知道如果林奇帮我逃狱，你肯定有份
l knew if Lynch helped me escape, you had to be part of it.
你和派克都不过是拿电板跟林奇演戏
You and Pike were making a play on those plates with Lynch,
你们出卖了林奇
and you turned on him.
就像出卖我们一样
The way you turned on us.
林奇想独吞
Lynch was never gonna cut us in.
他只是在利用我们
He was gonna use us.
保险起见才又算你一个
He brought you on as insurance.
他也没想到你会背叛最好的朋友
He never thought you'd betray your oldest living friend.
我只不过是先下手为强，汉尼拔 我是个军人
l just hit first, Hannibal. I'm a fighting man.
你是个骗子、叛徒！
You're a liar and a traitor!
那就别废话了，动手吧
Then don't draw this out. Kill me.
正有此意！
That's a fantastic idea!
哇！哇！
Whoa! Whoa!
大头，让我来
Bos, let me do this.
小帅，我不会杀任何人
Face, I ain't killing nobody.
你不会，博斯克，我会
You're not, Bosco. I am.
不管他说什么都别杀他，行吗？
No matter what he says, do not kill him, okay?
你们不愿意看是吧？那就转过身去
You guys don't wanna watch? Just turn your heads.
- 我不会站在你一边的 - 我也想要这孙子的小命
- I'm not gonna be party to it neither. - I wanna kill the son of a bitch, too,
可他现在是我们的王牌
but he's our ticket out.
他好歹就对过这么一次，听他的吧
He knows what he's talking about for once. Listen to him.
- 小帅，他是我们唯一的证人 - 默多克，默多克…
- Face, he is our only evidence. - Murdock, Murdock...
- 明白了吗？ - 他是罪魁祸首
Do you understand? - He put us here.
等他招供之后再崩了他也不迟，行吗？
You can blow his head off after he testifies, okay?
他自找的！
He's ruined it!
- 一定要考虑清楚，小帅 - 好了
- Think what you're doing, Face. All right.
- 你要是不行… - 伙计们，够了
- lf you can't handle it... Boys, enough.
够了！住手，小帅
Enough! That's enough, Face.
够了！退后！
Enough! Step down!
所有人出去
Everybody outside.
交给我
l got him.
- 我可不想你为难 - 小帅，出去
- I don't want you to have to do it. - Face, outside.
退下，士兵
Stand down, soldier.
小帅，马上！
Face. Now!
- 老顽固！ - 没事吧老兄？
- Fucking stupid. - You okay, man?
你早知道莫里森化装成阿拉伯人
You knew Morrison was masquerading as the Arab.
- 为什么不告诉我们？ - 我也没有十足的把握
- Why not share that? I wasn't 100% sure.
九成把握总有吧？
How about 99%?
那也不值得你一提吗？
Would you think it was worth mentioning then?
林奇，你到底怎么想的？
Lynch, what did you think?
你觉得我会当场把他打死？
You think l'd just kill him on the spot?
我以前肯定，现在也是
l was certain of it. I still am.
电板拿到了吗？
Do you have the plates?
没拿到就不会给你打电话了
l wouldn't be calling you if I didn't.
史密斯，交还电板，杀掉莫里森，重获自由
Smith, return the plates, kill Morrison, and reclaim your lives.
我要高层授权的特赦令
l want signed and authorized amnesty agreements
给我和我的所有队员
for myself and for each of my men.
要白宫、国务院和三军参谋长联席会议
From the White House, the State Department
共同给我签署
and the Joint Chiefs of Staff.
明白吗？
You hear me?
再给我点时间
I'm gonna need a little more time.
多久？
How much?
给我5分钟
Give me five minutes.
我等你
I'm waiting.
你还不明白吗，汉尼拔？
Don't you get it, Hannibal?
我们为了国家流血流汗甚至牺牲
We fight for them, we bleed for them, we die for them...
却连个屁的回报都没有
They don't give a rat's ass.
我们的生命
Death and destruction,
在他们眼里一文不值
they're selling it like it was on the goddamn commodities exchange.
不要推卸责任，这与他们无关
Don't push this off on them. This is not about them.
你就靠窃取10亿美金反战吗？
Your war protest was stealing billions of dollars!
你以为你是谁？
Who are you?
我是将军，而你只是个上校
l am a general. You are a colonel.
我让你往东你就不能往西，就这么简单
l say, "Jump," and you say, "How high?" End of story.
现在不用了
lt is now.
我在阿灵顿参加了你的葬礼
l saw your tomb at Arlington.
受的是国葬待遇
You died a national hero.
死太便宜你了
Death's too easy.
现在我们还需要另个一谎言
And the last thing we need now is another lie.
别这样，汉尼拔，求你了，你欠我那么多
Don't do this. Hannibal, please. You owe me that much.
你欠我的！
You owe me!
你要亲口告诉世人我们是清白的
You're gonna tell them we're innocent.
这是你欠我的
You owe me.
汉尼拔，没用了
Hannibal, it's meaningless.
你带弟兄这么抗争下去到底为了什么？
What are you fighting for now, you and those boys?
官阶？声誉？
Your ranks? Your reputations?
一文不值！
They're shit!
你们是罪犯！
You're convicts!
不管有没有电板，都无法洗脱罪名
Plates, no plates, you are federal fugitives,
你就等着他们过河拆桥吧
and when they're done with you, Hannibal, they just fucking burn you.
祖鲁1号，祖鲁1号，我是重剑，目标已锁定
Zulu one, Zulu one, this is Broadsword, you're clear to engage.
“重剑”，是你想的名字吗？
"Broadsword." Did you come up with that?
太有才了，“重剑”
That's awesome. "Broadsword."
“重剑”
"Broadsword."
头儿，你会这么做吗？
Boss, could you do that?
对我们？
To us?
就像莫里森？
What Morrison did?
不，我死也不出卖兄弟
No. Not in a million years.
没错，你当初也没料到会是这样
Yeah, but you didn't see it coming, though.
这事你瞒我们多久了？
How long did you know it was him?
你们是不是疯了？
Are you guys crazy?
我知道你是疯子 可是小帅，你干吗指责他呢？
l know you are, but, Face, are you accusing him?
嘿！嘿！
Hey! Hey!
就算上刀山下油锅我也不会出卖你们
l'd rather face a firing squad than betray you boys.
不能因为这个就散了
Don't let this tear us apart.
现在不行
Not now.
眼下正是最需要团结一致的时候
Not when we need each other like no other time before.
快闪！
Move!
喔，太帅了
Wow. That's awesome.
比好莱坞大片还刺激，不是吗？
That looks exactly like Call of Duty, doesn't it?
好了，都给我听好，不要记者
All right. Here's the deal. No press release.
也不要地方警察和媒体
Keep local law enforcement and media off- site.
设立3英里的警戒线，上空设禁飞区
Get a three- mile cordon, ditto the no- fly zone.
要一个中情局特勤组，务必把该死的电板夺回
Get an agency scrub team out there and get me the goddamn plates back.
德国警方已经在康尼克大厦把你的人一网打尽
The German police have your entire team in custody in the K?nigsbank Tower.
我可没什么手下，那都是史密斯的酒囊饭袋 我是个独行侠
l don't do teams, babe. That's Smith's bag. I'm strictly a solo act.
一向轻装上阵
l like to travel light.
忠诚这个词我的词典里是找不到的
Stuff like loyalty doesn't fit in the overhead bins.
我原以为你和史密斯是一伙的
l thought you and Smith were working together.
那你错了
You thought wrong.
是，我们有武器 不，你无权搜查我们
Yes, we have weapons. No, you may not wand us.
你要是想合作还来得及
lf you want to deal, we can deal.
那我即使豁上自己的前途也要
How about I dedicate my immediate future
把你绳之以法如何？
to destroying yours?
那你放聪明点赶在别人之前
How about you get smart and start dealing
跟我合作又如何？
before somebody else does?
前上尉
Former Captain.
嘿，哇、哇、哇
Hey, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
你要是没有一份像我这样的文件
Unless you've got a piece of paper that looks exactly like this one,
那这个刺儿头就要交给我了
then this troubled young loner belongs to me.
我们走
Let's go.
这帮人哪来这么大的能耐？
How the hell did they get an extradition order?
抱歉，派克，至少我们照章办事
Sorry, Pike. At least with me, there are rules.
中情局也有章法，只是比你们高级而已
ClA's got rules. Our rules are just cooler than yours.
- 走 - 听着，林奇
- Go. - You know, Lynch,
要是我把你关在这间屋子里 那才算是为大家做了件善事
if I could seal this room with you inside, l'd be doing the world a big favor.
嘴挺利的
(CLlCKS TONGUE) That's not nice.
是林奇？必须是！
Lynch? Had to be.
离火源近点，伙计们
Stay close to the fires, boys.
如果轰炸机还在，就探测不到我们的体热了
If that gunship is still around, it won't read our body heat.
这个混蛋林奇这么快就下毒手 真是不想拿回电板了
That idiot Lynch, so quick to kill us, didn't even bother locating the plates.
还坚持不用暴力吗，大头？
Where do we stand on the non- violence now, B.A.?
惹急你了？早该急了
You pissed? You should be.
谁管他妈的电板啊 只有莫里森才能帮我们洗脱罪名
Who gives a shit about the plates? Morrison was the only way to clear us.
现在他死了，我们也完了
And without Morrison, we got nothing.
- 现在怎么办，头儿？ - 我也不知道，默多克
- What do we do, boss? - I don't know, Murdock.
- 没辙了 - 我有
- I don't know. - I do.
我想我把林奇这家伙吃透了
This guy Lynch, I think I got him figured out.
- 有什么计划，小子？ - 我们怎么离开这儿？
- You got a plan, kid? - How do we get out of here?
给我20分钟
Give me 20 minutes.
现在莫里森死了，史密斯的战队也被灭掉了
So, Morrison's dead. Smith and his team are dead.
大约15分钟后就能锁定电板的位置
Another 1 5 minutes or so, we locate those engraving plates.
干什么？幸灾乐祸吗？
(SCOFFS) What is this? Are you gloating?
不，这叫以牙还牙
No, this is me beating you after you burned me.
- 我们本是一条战线的，记得吗？ - 不是我跟你
- We had a deal, remember? - Not you and me.
- 你、我还有莫里森 - 我和你没有直接联系
- You, me and Morrison. - Not you and me, directly.
而你们俩串通好了把我甩掉
And you two collude and cut me out.
嘿，就这么在车里杀人灭口？
Hey. What are you doing? ln the car?
要不要…要不要在车里动手？
Are we doing... Are we gonna do this in the car?
- 你真要这么做？ - 他会的
- You doing this? He's gonna do it.
就这样，好样的
Way to go. That's brilliant, right there.
你们要干什么？他在干什么？
What are you doing? What is he doing?
- 天呐！ - 没问题吧，卡尔？
- Jesus. - How's it going, Kyle?
- 没问题吧？ - 没问题
- You all right? - I'm good.
老兄，这可不叫没问题，你在干吗？
Brother, you are far from good. What are you doing?
这是欧洲产消声器
lt's a European silencer.
先往下压，然后逆时针拧，你就这么拿枪吗？
lt's a suppressor. Counter- clockwise. You're holding a gun like that?
你以前也这么干过居然还能活到现在？
You've held a gun like that before and you're still here?
太神奇了
That's amazing.
- 别拿那东西指… - 老天，求你了
- Don't point that thing... - Jesus. Final request,
别让这家伙开枪
don't let this guy shoot me, please.
如果索莎知道我们还活着
So, if Sosa knows we're alive...
她也会相信莫里森也活着
She'll believe Morrison is alive, too.
只能祈祷林奇还在窃听索莎的电话了
Let's just hope that Lynch still has Sosa's comm lines.
我是索莎
This is Sosa.
莫里森将军在我手上
General Morrison is in my possession.
什么？抱歉，我听不清，你是哪位？
What? I'm sorry. I can't hear you. Who is this?
- 好吧，这可不是闹着玩的 - 少废话
- Okay, this was not well thought out. No shit.
那你看看，是不是还要我教你怎么杀我？
l mean, look at this. Am I to teach you how to kill me?
嘿，帮我个忙，好吗？用枪口…
Hey, do me a favor, all right? Put the barrel...
用枪口指着我的头
Put the gun flush to my head.
- 你确定？ - 对，就像这样
Are you sure? - There you go, right there.
- 你是不是疯了？ - 在你打伤你同事之前
- ls that going to go through? - Before you hurt somebody besides me.
枪就归我了，冷静，冷静
There you go. We're okay. We're okay.
永远不要手铐铐在一个人的背后
Never cuff a man in a seated position with his hands behind his back.
这样你就看不到他手上的动作
Makes it impossible to see the hands.
挺能干啊
That was cool.
- 喜欢吗？ - 喜欢
- You like that? - I like that.
超喜欢
- I like that a lot.
你没事吧，白痴？
Are you all right, you idiot?
- 你挨一拳试试！ - 还不把他铐上
- Yeah. lt was a good hit. - Please handcuff him.
你们不再需要手铐了，我很听话的
We don't need to use them again. We don't need the cuffs.
你以为自己是谁？
Who are you talking to?
- 布拉德，手机还是手枪？ - 天呐
- Brad, phone or gun. - Jesus.
- 手机还是手枪，选一个 - 嘿，嘿
Phone or gun. Pick. - Hey, hey.
- 把枪放下 - 嘿，是莫里森出卖你的，不是我
- Put the gun down. - Hey, I didn't burn you. Morrison did.
真想一枪崩了你
l really wanna shoot you.
快来听听这个，长官
You gotta hear this, sir.
是史密斯吗？
ls this Smith?
是前上校给前上尉打电话
From a former colonel to a former captain,
我知道被你锁定位置之前我有30秒
l know l've got about 30 seconds before you lock this signal.
- 所以听好，我们能证明自己的清白 - 就把它放在地板上？
- So listen, we can prove our innocence. - Leave that on the floor like that?
好吧，我再问一遍
Okay. All right. Now, go back.
你刚才是不是说你抓住了莫里森？
Did you say you have Morrison? You have General Morrison?
- 没错 - 他还活着？
- Correct. - You have him alive?
活得好好的，尽管我们差点被林奇一锅端
And well, despite Lynch trying to wipe us out wholesale.
现在很难跟你解释，但莫里森的供词能脱我们的罪
Too much to explain now but Morrison's testimony frees us
也能治林奇的罪
and fries Lynch.
哦
Uh- oh.
除非电板也在你手上
Well, not without the plates.
就在我手上
Also in mypossession.
记住，林奇认为我们已经死了 那我们就继续演戏给他看
Remember, Lynch thinks we're dead, and I want to keep it that way.
- 好的，没问题 - 给我支笔
All right. We'll deal. - Give me a pen.
- 时间地点？ - 有笔吗？谁有笔？
- Where and when? - Got a pen? Anybody got a pen?
- 洛杉矶码头，48小时后，凌晨 - 你还在用钢笔？
LA docks, 48 hours, dawn. - You still use a pen?
我交出莫里森和电板
l deliver Morrison and the plates.
作为交换，我要民事法庭的复审
ln return, I want a retrial in front of a civilian court.
好的，成交
All right. We'll deal.
洛杉矶码头，48小时后
LA docks, 48 hours from now.
要是敢耍花样，行动就取消
Any bullshit from your end, and that's it, deal's off.
- 追到了吗？ - 没有
- Did we get him? - No.
派克
Pike.
你相信第二次机会吗？
You believe in second chances?
嗯…
Uh...
现在信了
l do now.
说太多了？
Too much?
我觉得刚刚好
l thought you were spot- on.
该我了
My turn.
手机拿好
Hold on to that phone.
我是索莎
This is Sosa.
你好，美女
Hello, beautiful.
谢谢
Thank you.
他们俩不会被人发现吧？看看大头
They got the raw end of the deal, didn't they? Look at B.A.
裹得跟个香蕉似的
He looks like a huge banana.
早上好，朋友
Good morning, my friend.
早上好
Good morning.
拉比·宾奇·拉比诺维茨？
Rabbi Binky Rabinowitz?
我给他的哪国护照啊？
What passport did I give you?
你来自坦桑尼亚，我母亲就来自坦桑
You're from Tanzania. My mother is from Tanzania.
- 该死！ - 到底怎么了？
- Oh, shit. - What the hell happened?
- …我是个信仰犹太教的非洲人 - 这里是6号柜台…
- ...converting Africans to Judaism. This is station six...
诸如此类
Stuff like that.
我们准备闪人，右边有3个钉子
Let's get ready to move. There's three to my right.
我身后有2个，东北出口有1个
There's two behind me and one at the northeast exit.
等等
Wait a sec.
再见
Shalom.
- 他在干嘛？ - 默多克又满嘴跑火车了
- What's he doing? - lt's Murdock. Telling his life story.
他来了
There is a God.
- 你会说斯瓦希利语？ - 你不会？
- You speak Swahili? - You don't?
准备干活了，小子
You got enough to work with, kid?
还用说
We will.
你跟我现在都快爱上横渡大西洋了
You and I have some major favors moving across the mid- Atlantic right now.
那是艘远洋渡船，驶往黑市深处
lt's a deep- sea freighter, shipping strictly black- market merch.
我们怎么登船？
How do we get out to her?
船，是艘老船
A boat. A plain old boat.
我说什么来着，默多克，坐船多有情调啊
This is what I'm talking about, Murdock. Traveling the open seas in style.
我就喜欢水路旅行，超级怀旧 过去人们都喜欢，安全
This is the way I like to travel. Classy- like. The way people used to, safe.
- 是啊… - 有船谁坐飞机啊
- Yeah... - We don't need a plane.
听着，博斯克，真希望哪天能治好你的恐飞症
You know, Bosco, hopefully one day we'll get you over your fear of flying.
什么？
What?
嘿，那不是船！
Hey, that ain't a boat!
今天是没戏了
Just not today.
默多克，你忘记我是怎么说的了？
Murdock, don't you remember what I said?
- 我说把他弄晕… - 把他弄晕…
- I said you have to catch him... - You have to catch him...
…就得把他背上 …就得把他背上
- ...after you inject him. - ...after you inject him.
我错了
My bad.
该死！我的头
(GROANS) Damn it! My head, man.
- 椰粉馅饼，你的最爱 - 给我拿来，笨蛋
- Coconut- curry tapenade, your favorite. - Give me that, fool.
加肉末了吗？
You get them toast points?
当然，精致肉末
Voilo. Toast points.
你们又把我弄晕了？
Y'all knocked me out again, huh?
听着，给你打针，把你搞晕
Okay, now, the whole injection, knocking out,
他俩的主意
Hannibal and Face.
椰粉馅饼，我的诚意
The curry tapenade, Murdock.
我怎么感觉是脸先着地的？
Why do I feel like I fell on my face?
嗯？给我说清楚
Huh? Tell me that.
呃…
Uh...
林奇是个矛盾体
Lynch is a paradox.
默多克，喝完杯子给我
Murdock, you done with that?
本该隐姓埋名 却又频频招摇过市
This is a guy who needs anonymity, but he loves theatricality.
他只适合玩权术，不适合玩技术
He's an administrator, he's not an operator.
在哪？
Where is it?
很好
Very nice.
只要有机会，他总会远离是非中心
So he stays as far away from the point of impact as possible,
把罪责脱的一干二净
and never gets his hands dirty if he can help it.
但我们要让他吃吃苦头
But we're gonna change all that.
雕虫小技
You can't hustle a hustler, fool.
这东西要远离火星、火苗，闪光灯也不行
No sparks, no flames, not even a flashlight near this stuff.
小心，小心
Easy, easy.
这家伙做坏事从来不出头
This guy is never at the flashpoint of anything.
都是躲得远远的坐镇指挥
He's safe and sound somewhere, pulling the strings.
妈妈，妈妈
Mama. Mama.
嘿，头儿，干吗弄这么多爆竹？
Hey, boss. Why so many of these damn things anyway?
因为这次真要大开杀戒了，朋友
Because overkill is underrated, my friend.
所以我们要揭开他的真面目
So we're gonna bring this guy down to ground level.
妈妈，妈…
(DlSTORTED) Mama. Mama.
我在这儿，林奇，林奇
(DlSTORTED) This way, Lynch. Lynch.
逼他亲自上阵
The last place he'd ever want to be.
然后当着全世界揭开他的丑恶嘴脸
Then you put him on display for the whole world to see.
有问题吗？
Any questions?
有事吗，头儿？
What's up, boss man?
嘿，大头
Hey, B.A.
真要大开杀戒了吗？
lt's gonna get heavy, isn't it?
我不能保证不会
Well, I can't promise you it won't.
听我给你读段话
Let me read you something real quick.
“藉由暴力取胜无异于失败”
"Victory attained by violence is tantamount to defeat,
“因为胜利如此短暂”
"for it is momentary."
甘地
Gandhi.
“藉由非暴力掩饰内心懦弱”
"lt is better to be violent if there is violence in our hearts,
“还不如释放心中已有的暴力”
"than to put on the cloak of non- violence to cover impotence."
谁说的？
Who said that?
还是甘地
Same guy.
甘地敢于为自己的信念而战斗
Gandhi wasn't afraid to fight for the things he believed in.
你的信念又是什么，大头？
What is it you believe in, B.A.?
生命就像一出戏
(SlNGlNG) Forlife is but an opera
关掉了对吗？
lt's off, isn't it?
我觉得应该高一点
l think it's higher.
不，很好，不是它的问题，默多克
No, it's good. lt's not that, Murdock.
小帅，到底怎么了？
Face, what's wrong? Come on, man.
不知道，哥们，只是在琢磨我们的计划
l don't know, man. I'm just thinking past this.
听着，我们总能全身而退
You know, we've always come back alive,
就因为有了头儿的周密计划
the four of us, 'cause of the old man.
- 我知道 - 可我不是他
- I know. - I'm not him.
小帅，我知道
Face, I know this.
默多克，我不是汉尼拔
Murdock, I'm not Hannibal.
这里面谁最输不起，小帅？
Who has the most to lose on this, Face?
是我
Me.
我相信你
And I trust you.
我知道
Yeah, I know,
可你疯了
but you're crazy.
不严重
Not that crazy.
洛杉矶码头
猎物就要出现
Our eagles may have landed.
所有人准备
Everybody ready to roll?
收到，1队待命
Copy Team one on the move.
明白，2队待命
Acknowledged. Team to en route.
好了，伙计们，准备好了吗？
All right, guys, everybody ready?
好戏就要开始了
Curtain's about to come up.
开工
Show time.
史密斯出来了，盯住他
That's Smith right there. Watch him.
地面分队就位了吗？
Ground team is in position?
已经就位
Standing by.
就位
ln position.
狙击1号，就位
Shoot Team One. Affirmative.
瞭望1号，就位
Spotter One. 1 0- 8.
从现在开始使用暗语通话
Let's chattermark on comms for now.
莫里森是探戈舞王，电板是包裹
Morrison's the primary tango. Plates are the package.
请讲
Yeah.
好，好，他在跟索莎通话，给我接上
Okay, okay, he's talking to Sosa. I want this call.
你撒谎了，索莎，我们说好的
You lied to me, Sosa. We had a deal.
我现在就要听那个该死的电话…
l want that goddamn call in my... Thank you.
我们是说好的，不过计划有变
We had a deal, but I'm changing the deal.
你是不是在耍我，索莎？是不是耍我？
Are you kidding me, Sosa Are you kidding me?
情况很复杂，现在不是你做主
This is a complicated exchange and you have no play here.
听着，否则就继续做你的逃犯
Listen, or remain at- large fugitives
- 永世不得翻身 - 呃，不！不！不！
- for the foreseeable future. - Uh- oh. No! No, no.
你要想清楚，我手上有莫里森和电板
For God sakes, l've got Morrison here and the plates.
我暴露了，索莎，暴露了！
I'm exposed, Sosa. Exposed!
我们不能在码头交易
We're not doing this on the docks.
听我说，我们不会上门送死的
Now listen to me, we're not turning ourselves in.
给我听清楚，我们不会上门送死
Now you listen to me, we're not turning ourselves in.
要么乖乖照我说的做，要么拉倒
l need you to do it on my terms or nothing at all.
去你的，去你妈的，索莎！
To hell with that, and to hell with you, Sosa!
啊，她把他惹火了
Ah. She burned him.
小帅，大头，准备撤，索莎耍了我们
Face, B.A., we're bugging out. Sosa's jammed us.
默多克，马上把直升机开过来
Murdock, get the chopper down here in 1 0.
快看，他在转移人质
Okay, he's moving him.
瞄准了吗？他在转移人质
You got him? He's moving him.
拜托你冷静一下
For the love of God, relax.
我很冷静，他就是在转移嘛
l am relaxed. He's moving him.
别这么做，汉尼拔，求你了
Don't do this. Hannibal, please.
- 是莫里森，没错，干掉他 - 等等，他有没有电板？
- That's Morrison, right there. Take him. - Wait, does he have the plates?
电板在史密斯手上，快开枪
Smith has the plates. Go now.
- 开枪，他在那儿，快开枪 - 已经瞄准莫里森，开火
- Take him, he's right there. Kill him. - l've got Morrison, taking a shot.
太及时了，小子
A little too close for comfort, kid.
发生什么事了？
What just happened?
他在干什么？
What the hell is he doing?
他们去哪了？回答我！
Where are they? Somebody talk to me.
他们被集装箱压扁了还是怎么着？
Come on, did that thing crush them or what?
还是塑料杯子挪起来比较顺手
This was a hell of a lot easier when it was just three plastic cups.
所有人冷静，盯紧，不要轻举妄动
Everybody just be cool. Pay attention. No hasty moves.
要打倒林奇必须有三个要素
So, you beat a guy like Lynch by drawing him in with three things.
他们究竟在干什么？
What the hell are they doing?
声东击西
Distraction.
哇！哇！哇！搞什么飞机？
Whoa, whoa, whoa! What is happening?
调虎离山
Diversion.
这是调虎离山！盯紧货柜
This is a diversion! Stay eagle on those containers.
他们打算冲出去，开火！
They're breaking for the exits! Open fire!
别正面冲突！退后！
Do not engage! Back off!
地面分队，上！
Ground teams, engage!
妈的！
Holy shit!
地面分队，给我上！
Ground team, re- engage.
你们上史密斯的当了
You are being played by Smith.
别被他牵着鼻子走，林奇，放聪明点
He's trying to draw your eye line, Lynch. Come on, be smart.
抓住他们！抓住他们！
Take them! Take them! Take them! Take them!
注意！注意上面！是贝克和巴库斯！
Contact! Tower house and bow! lt's Peck and Baracus!
各个击破
And division.
中计了！撤退！撤退！
lt's a trap! Pull back! Pull back!
- 都他妈给我撤！ - 不不不！
- Get the hell out of there! - No, no, no.
怎么回事？怎么了？
What is happening? What is going on?
漂亮，小子
Nice one, kid.
是贝克和巴库斯！
lt's Peck and Baracus!
- 打死他们！ - 闭嘴！不用你教我！
- Shoot them! - Shut up! I know what I'm doing.
好吧，兔崽子，来点真格的
Okay, paintballers, time to go pro.
大头，执行第二步计划
B.A., get to your secondary position.
好吧，大佬
Okay. Game- changer.
让你的白痴计划见鬼去吧
Here's what I think of your best- laid plans.
该死！
Shit!
老天爷！
Jesus Christ!
你的阴谋休想得逞，史密斯
So much for the grand scheme, Smith.
他妈的怎么回事？
What the hell was that?
小帅，发生什么事了？
Face, what the hell was that?
派克发射了火箭弹！把船打了个洞！
Pike hit the ship with a SMAW! He punched a hole in the hull!
你的计划呢？
What about the plan?
被派克打乱了！随机应变吧！
Pike just blew up the plan! We are ad- libbing!
博斯克，离开那儿！
Bosco, get out of there!
我去帮汉尼拔
I'm going for Hannibal.
- 掩护我，我去找电板 - 遵命，长官
- Cover me. I'm going for those plates. - Yes, sir.
船要沉了，赶快走！
The boat is going over! Get out of there!
博斯克，坚持住！
Bos, hang on!
天呐！
Oh! Jeez!
妈的！
Shit.
博斯克，派克占据有利地形，我快没子弹了
Bosco, Pike's got the high ground. I'm running low on ammo, man.
妈的！
Shit!
你好吗，帅哥？
How are you doing, handsome?
该死，把武器扔掉，好样的
Shit, can you cycle that weapon. Nice work.
天杀的，战友跟子弹
Jeez, close friends and bullets.
怎么最需要的时候却偏偏不见了呢？
Where are they when you need them?
不是私人恩怨，可你看这儿
Don't take this too personally, but look here,
微笑，等着开花吧
smile, wait for the flash.
巴库斯
Baracus.
博斯克！
Bosco!
林奇
(WHlSPERlNG) Lynch.
Lynch.
来啊林奇
Come on, Lynch.
林奇
Lynch.
出来啊，史密斯！少他妈废话！
Come on, Smith! Stop bullshitting.
林奇，来啊，林奇！
Lynch. Come on, Lynch.
林奇…
Lynch...
来找我呀
Where am l?
来啊林奇
Come on, Lynch.
林奇
Lynch.
来找我呀，林奇
Where am l, Lynch?
来啊林奇
Come on, Lynch.
林奇，林奇，林奇，林奇
Lynch, Lynch, Lynch, Lynch.
林奇！
Lynch!
你在这儿啊，汉尼拔！让我好找啊！
(WHOOPS) There you are, Hannibal. Been looking all over for you.
嘿，别让这点小拳脚吓倒
Hey, don't let the scarf fool you.
我的泰拳也还不错，柔道则更胜一筹，不过…
My muay Thai is pretty good. My jujitsu is a little better, but...
跟你在码头上放烟花、换货柜
You had this whole sleight- of- hand thing going with the containers
烧汽车的手段比起来还差不少
and the cars, and the fireworks. "Lynch, Lynch, Lynch!"
让我很不爽 你还给派克火箭筒
God, that's annoying. But you give Pike a rocket.
可惜你太天真了
There's your monkey wrench.
汉尼拔，别这么做
Hannibal, don't do this.
知道吗，史密斯，你本可以成为全世界的佼佼者
You know, Smith, you could have the best recipe in the world...
- 你欠我那么多 - …可惜你太不识相
You owe me that much. - ...but you drop a few bullets
- 站错了队 - 汉尼拔，别这么做
- into the batter... - Hannibal, don't do this.
- 林奇，不！ - 汉尼拔，求你了
Lynch, no! - Hannibal, please.
老天
Oh, God.
…这无疑是死路一条
...and that cake don't bake.
哦哦！你的证人，死在你的抢下，你惨了
Uh- oh. Your witness, your gun, your problem.
让你为国捐躯，真是抱歉
You served your country well. Excuse me.
你好，本，你让我找的好苦啊 （本杰明·富兰克林：百元美钞）
Hello, Ben, where have you been all my life?
看看，汉尼拔，我们都老大不小了
Look at us, Hannibal. Couple of grown men.
我是鼻青，你是脸肿
I'm bleeding. You're bleeding.
别起来
(TUTTlNG) Don't get up.
真该死！
God damn it!
你的泰拳跟柔道一样烂，林奇
Your muay Thai is as bad as yourjujitsu, Lynch.
下次还是用枪吧
Better stick with a gun.
你要是敢给我一把上膛的手枪 我保证送你上路
You put a loaded weapon in my hand, l'll put a bullet in your head.
我说到做到
l told you I would shoot you.
防弹衣可以救你一命
Kevlar saved your life.
可我要是爆你头看你它还能否救得了你
Thing is, it doesn't do much good if I pop you in the head.
把它重新熔铸就可以
lt does if you melt it down.
汉尼拔，别这么做
Hannibal, don't do this.
- 汉尼拔，求你了 - 要打倒林奇
- Hannibal, please. So, you beat a guy like that
必须有三个要素
by drawing him in with three things.
- 声东击西 - 哇！哇！哇！搞什么飞机？
- Distraction. - Whoa, whoa, whoa! What is happening?
调虎离山
Diversion.
各个击破
And division.
汉尼拔，杀了我
Hannibal, don't leave me alive.
然后当着全世界揭开他的丑恶嘴脸
Then you put him on display for the whole world to see.
这他妈…
What the...
很好
That's good.
惊喜
Surprise.
伯雷斯探员
Agent Burress.
你叫我什么？
What did you call me?
万斯·伯雷斯探员？是不是你的名字？
Agent Vance Burress? lsn't that your name?
至少我的拘捕令上是这个名字
At least that's the name l've got on this warrant here,
除非你手上也有一份像我一样的…
and unless you have a piece of paper that looks exactly like...
你学的还真快
That's funny. That's what I said.
她在学我说话
She's quoting me.
轻点，轻点
Easy, easy.
你因涉嫌谋杀未遂
You're under arrest for attempted murder,
触犯《民事欺诈给付请求法》
violations of the Civil False Claims Act,
窃取政府绝密印钞电板而被捕
and the theft of top secret government engraving plates.
轻点
Easy.
我觉得计划还蛮顺利
l guess the plan went okay,
虽然派克把船给炸了，这一点是计划外的
considering Pike did blow up the boat, which I didn't account for at all.
子弹没有打穿
Bullets didn't go through.
汉尼拔，别这么做，汉尼拔，求你了
Hannibal, don't do this. Hannibal, please.
感觉如何，伙计？
How are you feeling, man?
不…不怎么样
Not... Not good.
- 怎么了？ - 不怎么样
- What's wrong? - Not good.
清醒了
- I feel sane.
其实我早想冲你脑袋开一枪了
l should have shot you in the head a long time ago.
我都能感觉到你的焦虑了，奇不奇怪？
ls it crazy that I'm feeling your anxiety right now?
我看起来很焦虑吗？
Do I look anxious to you?
你觉得打败我了？
You think I'm beaten?
我流的是血，不是汗
I'm bleeding, I'm not sweating.
把他带走，兄弟们，走吧，小公主
Let's take him out of here, guys. Go ahead, princess.
撞伤和碰伤有什么区别？
What's the difference between a concussion and a contusion?
- 管他呢，兄弟，都是伤 - 默多克，干得漂亮
- lt don't matter, bro. You tore up. Murdock, that was beautiful.
你是对的，头盔很管用
You were right. The helmet worked.
番茄酱很唬人
Ketchup worked great.
你立大功了，好点吗？
You did a great job. You okay?
- 还行 - 好点了吧？
- Yeah. Got your bell rung?
下次还是让汉尼拔拿主意吧
Just let Hannibal make the plans next time.
- 没问题 - 没问题
- Oh. Okay. - Okay?
这次心有不安了吗，大头？
How's the conscience, big guy?
相当安
At peace.
别停机
Keep it turning.
我们的人已经在出口等候了
We already got them on the exits.
- 已经划定两英里的禁飞区 - 你们哪位是索莎？
- We got a two- mile no- fly zone here. - Which one of you is Sosa?
- 我是 - 我需要跟你谈一谈
- I am. I am. - I need to talk to Sosa.
现在你的人犯正式移交给
As of right now your prisoner is to be remanded
- 联邦政府羁押 - 我有对他的拘捕令
- into federal custody. - I have a warrant for this man.
- 但是现在… - 老实说，我是个医生…
As of right now... - l'll tell you what... I'm a doc.
我给你瞧瞧伤势，我能帮你的
Let me doctor you up. Let me help you out.
需要缝合伤口吗？你肯定需要缝合
Do you need stitches? Please tell me you need stitches.
我肯定能把你缝的天衣无缝
l can stitch you up really good.
诸位
Gentlemen.
中央情报局
The Central lntelligence Agency
信奉也表现出深切的道德关切
believes in and evinces a profound moral ethic,
以及一如既往的专业水准
as well as an unshakeable professional standard.
同时，我们也愿意为所发生的一切
As such, we would like to extend our most sincere apologies
奉上最诚挚的歉意
for what's happened here.
- 再见，上帝保佑你们 - 你们打算带他去哪儿？
- Good day and God bless. - Where are you taking him?
带谁？
Who?
还不知道你叫什么
l never got your name.
我叫林奇
My name is Lynch.
我猜也是
Of course it is.
他也叫林奇？
Did he just say Lynch?
随他去吧
Let it go.
嘿，别碰我
Hey. Do not touch me.
别乱来，伙计们
Take it easy, guys.
所有人退后，退后！
Everybody, stand down! Stand down!
- 去拿电板 - 所有人退后！
- Get those plates. Everybody, stand down!
- 这是命令，嘿，你，退后！ - 你怎么回事？
- That's an order. Hey, you, stand down. What is wrong with you?
中尉
- Lieutenant.
长官，您什么时候到的？我不知道您…
Sir, when did you arrive? I had no idea...
- 先等一下 - 是，长官
- Just give me a minute. - Yes, sir.
把你的手拿开，兄弟
Get your hands off me, tough guy.
真是一团糟啊，好在电板找回来了
Well, that's one hell of a mess. But we did get the plates.
很遗憾，我还要指控你们非法逃脱监禁
Unfortunately, I'm gonna have to charge you all with escaping lawful custody.
什么？汉尼拔，这家伙在说什么？
What? Hannibal, what is this guy talking about?
大头，即便我们入了冤狱，可逃狱终究是不对的
B.A., we were wrongly convicted, but it's still illegal to break out ofjail.
检察官大人，史密斯和他的小队
Director McCready, Smith and his team
在拯救电板行动中立下汗马功劳
were instrumental in recovering those plates.
可他们仍是联邦特级逃犯，我总要有个交代
They're still level- 1 0 federal fugitives and I need that off my desk.
太扯淡了，长官
This is chickenshit, sir.
没错，你知道吗？对他们而言也许是扯淡
Yeah, well, you know what? Perhaps for them, it is chickenshit,
但是对你，上尉，我们决定给你官复原职
but for you, Captain, we're re- promoting you to your former rank.
听着，他们将被移交给
So, look, they're gonna be delivered
位于长滩的美国法警
to the U.S. Marshals Service here in Long Beach.
- 有一架C-5运输机… - 我了解，可是…
- And there should be a C- 5 transport... - I understand, but...
…将在半小时后抵达停机坪
...on the tarmac in half an hour.
- 规定就是规定 - 可这不公平，长官
- This needs to be done. - This is really unfair, sir.
- 太扯淡了 - 我是逃脱术大师
- This is bullshit. - I'm like Harry Houdini.
手铐奈何不了我
l chew through your cuffs.
- 起来，起来，都进去！ - 起来！
- Get up. Step up. Get in there! - Step up!
- 快走，麻利点！ - 等等，先等等
Let's go. Get moving. - Stop. Wait, stop.
- 快走 - 等等
Move it. - Wait.
- 他们这么做是不对的 - 枪打出头鸟嘛
- This is so wrong. - lt got a little aggressive.
- 不用担心 - 这是不对的
- Don't worry about it. - This is really, really wrong,
我会想尽一切办法救你们的
and I'm going to do everything I can to fix it.
- 我知道你会 - 对不起，小帅
- I know you will. - I'm so sorry, Face.
好样的，小帅
Nice plan, Face.
好啊，刚抓住林奇，我们就又进监狱了
Yeah. We just traded Lynches, and we're going back to prison.
我们找回了电板，可以堂堂正正做人了
We returned the plates. We can hold our heads high.
我们光明磊落
We did the right thing.
是啊，可他们是怎么对我们的？太不讲理了
Yeah, and look what they did to us. This is some bullshit.
我们又被涮了，汉尼拔
They burned us again, Hannibal.
相信政府就没什么好下场
We trusted the system and it turned on us.
记住，伙计们，不管事情看起来多么偶然
Remember, boys, no matter how random things might appear,
背后总有原因的
there is still a plan. Kid.
请原谅我偷用你的台词，头儿…
Well, I don't mean to steal your line, boss, but...
- 说吧 - 这就叫老谋深算
Yeah. - I love it when a plan comes together.
<i>政府通缉人员</i>
Still wanted by the government,
<i>他们无往不破</i>
they survive as soldiers of fortune.
<i>假如你麻烦缠身</i>
If you have a problem,
<i>假如你走投无路</i>
if no one else can help,
<i>假如你能找到他们</i>
and if you can find them,
<i>建议你雇佣</i>
maybe you can hire
天龙特攻队
the A- Team.
谢谢观赏 特效重制 IKK